大家好 声音不要太大
Hello, everyone. Not too loud.
希望这样可以
I hope it's fine.
太好了
Perfect.
那我们就开始这个工作坊 很快会先做一下自我介绍
So, yeah, we'll start to kick up the workshop and we'll introduce ourselves shortly.
但首先我们想先给大家看这一页幻灯片
But first, we just wanted to present the slide,
因为这基本就是今年的领英
because that's basically LinkedIn this year.
这是那种你问ChatGPT时
It's the type of content that when you ask chatGPT,
它基本就会给你这种内容
that's basically what you get.
一个非常通用的回答
A very generic response.
而这个回答本身有不少问题 是我们不太愿意看到的
And there are a few things wrong with this actual response that we don't really like seeing.
最明显的是那些烂词套话
The obvious ones are the slop words,
也就是AI烂文/AI糟粕内容 比如那些大家都熟悉的 Delve 和 intricacies
the AI slop, so all the Delve, intricacies that we all know about.
但问题不止这些 好在
But there are more... and fortunately,
这里面倒是连破折号都没有
there aren't even some em dashes in there.
但还有其他问题
But there are some other problems,
比如那种 呃 好吧
like the... all right.
这些行有点对不齐
The lines are a bit off.
但更普遍的问题是
But the most that is more general,
像“多数公司都忽略”“大多数人都忽略”这种说法
like most companies miss or most people miss,
它经常这么写
it does that often.
这些就是一些领英帖子里的例子
These are some examples from LinkedIn posts,
他们都在说“多数团队”
where they all say most teams,
“大多数人” 或者这里的“大多数AI项目”
most people, or here, most AI projects.
而且我自己其实也犯过这种毛病
And I'm actually guilty of that one.
所以我们一边做一边学习改进
So we learn as we do.
还有幻觉问题 或者像这里 过时的信息
And there are some other problems with hallucinations or here, outdated information.
很明显 这是上周刚生成的
Obviously, this was generated like last week,
但GPT-4已经不是最新的前沿模型了
and GPT-4 is not state of the art.
同样 还有很多我们经常看到的AI套话糟粕
And likewise, there are some AI phrases slop that we see a lot.
比如最典型的“快速发展中”
The obvious rapidly evolving one,
还有那句经典的
but also the classic,
“关键不在于某某”
it's not about something,
“而在于别的什么” 这种它特别爱生成
but something else that it generates a lot.
而最糟糕的是 这些内容通常非常空洞浅薄
And the worst of all is that typically this is really meaningless and shallow.
几乎没有任何价值或实用信息
It doesn't provide any value or anything useful.
所以我们真正需要的是围绕这些语言模型做扎实的研究和严谨的写作
And so what we need here is a proper research and proper writing around these language models.
为了让大家更了解这个工作坊的背景
And to give more context of this workshop,
我们Towards AI 主要在做课程和大量视频
we basically at Towards AI create courses and tons of videos,
培训以及各种技术内容
training, and technical content.
为此我们需要围绕AI工程创作技术内容
And to do that, we need to create technical content around AI engineering.
所以我们需要技术写作者
So we need technical writers,
也就是既要有AI工程师
which means we need AI engineers,
也要有写作者 编辑 一起反复打磨
writers, editors that iterate together,
还要花很多时间去讲好故事
and a lot of time to create a good storytelling,
写出一篇好文章 一节好课程
just a good article, good lesson,
或者总体上一个好视频
or good video in general,
而这一切最终都非常烧钱
which in the end costs a lot of money.
所以我们尝试把这个流程自动化
So what we try to do is to automate this process,
我们确实做到了 起码是部分自动化
which we did, or at least a part of it,
因为还有一部分必须由人来完成 才能讲好故事 让人产生共鸣
because another part is really a human thing to make a good story and relate to the others.
所以这就是我们所做的事情
And so that's what we did.
我们搭建了一个系统 来替代“先做非常深入的研究 再进行技术写作”的整套流程
We built a system for replacing this whole process of doing a very thorough research and then technical writing.
它的做法是 我们先给一个主题
So what it does is we give a topic,
比如“什么是RAG工程”
like what is RAG engineering,
然后我们自研的深度研究智能体会去检索各种网站和工具
and we have our own deep research agent that will search various websites and tools,
利用这些工具完成很多操作
use tools to do lots of things,
接着由另一个系统来写真正的技术文章 包含代码
and then another system to write an actual technical article with code,
图片 而且理想情况下 没有那些烂文套话
images, and ideally non-slop writing in there.
实际上 这个系统
And actually, this system,
既然我们要做课程
since we build courses,
我们就用它来做了一门课程
we used it to build a course,
教大家如何构建这个系统
to teach it to build this system.
所以整体来说 这是个非常有趣的项目
So it was a really fun project to do in general,
它也让我们能大量迭代测试 并直接从学生那里获得用户反馈
and it allowed us to iterate and test a lot and to have user feedback directly with our students.
所以体验非常不错
So it's really nice.
这就是我们想在这两个小时的工作坊里分享的内容
And that's what we try to share here in this two-hour workshop,
或者说 至少是一个更精简的版本 规模更小
or at least a much more compact version with a smaller,
更简单的深度研究系统 加上一个专门面向短内容的写作智能体 用于
simpler deep research system and a writing agent strictly for shorter content for a
领英风格的帖子
LinkedIn type of post.
同时我们也会分享在构建过程中学到的东西
And also, we try to share what we learned building it.
你们可以打开或获取这个GitHub代码仓库
And you can open or get the GitHub repository.
它是公开的 在前30分钟里
It's public. In the first 30 minutes,
我只会用幻灯片讲解
I will just talk with slides,
所以暂时用不到代码仓库
so you won't be needing it.
但之后我的同事会带大家看代码
But after that, my colleagues will jump in with the code,
所以到时候有仓库会比较方便
so it might be worth to have it.
我们稍后会再把这个二维码放出来
And we will show this QR code again later on,
这样你们就能及时获取
so you can get that on time.
总之 我会先讲我们学到的东西 以及一些术语
But basically, I will cover what we learned and some terminologies,
因为我们是一家教育公司
because we are an educational company,
这正是我们喜欢做的事
and that's what we like to do.
所以我会先讲一些基础内容 让大家站在同一水平线上
And so I will cover some basics to bring everyone to the same level,
至少是按照我们对这些概念的定义来对齐
or at least to our definitions of things,
然后分享我们在构建过程中得到的经验
and share what we learned by building it.
接着由萨姆里迪来讲真正的深度研究智能体
And then Samriddhi will take over to talk about the actual deep research agent,
然后继续后面的内容
and follow with the rest.
那我们是谁呢
So who are we?
我这边是Towards AI的首席技术官兼联合创始人
On my end, I'm the CTO and co-founder of Towards AI.
我叫路易-弗朗索瓦
My name is Louis-François,
在ChatGPT出现之前 我一直是做AI的博士生
and I was a PhD student in AI until ChatGPT came out,
之后我基本就转成全职教育工作者 并创立Towards AI 专注做这件事
where I basically switched to being an educator full-time and creating Towards AI to focus around that.
我做讲解论文的视频已经有七年了
I've been doing videos to explain research paper for seven years now,
现在我更多聚焦在AI工程
and obviously right now I'm more around AI engineering,
从2020年起我就一直在这个领域做开发
and I've been developing in the space since 2020.
从我加入的第一家初创公司开始
At the first startup,
我就是做这方面的工作
I was hired at.
接下来我就把时间交给萨姆里迪 让她自我介绍一下
And so I will leave Samriddhi to introduce herself.
大家好 我是萨姆里迪
Hi everyone, I'm Samriddhi.
我是一名机器学习工程师
I am a machine learning engineer.
我同时也是技术写作者和顾问 帮助Towards AI 发展
I'm also a technical writer and a consultant helping Towards AI grow,
很高兴见到大家
so nice to meet you all.
大家好，我是保罗，我已经做软件开发八年了
Hello everyone, I'm Paul and I'm building a software for eight years,
我也在教授AI相关内容这个领域深耕了四年多
and I've been into the teaching AI space for four plus years,
我还是畅销书《LLM工程师手册》的作者
and I'm also the author of the LLM Engineer's Handbook bestseller,
今天很高兴能给大家带来这场工作坊
and I'm excited to show this workshop to you guys today.
好，那我先来做个介绍……我们一向是从一个问题开始
Perfect, so I'll start with introducing... we always start with a problem,
在这里这个问题会比较泛
and here it's pretty general.
我先来介绍一下AI工程的问题空间
I start introducing the AI engineering problem space,
本质上是说，作为AI工程师，我们所有的决策都受制于
where basically it's just that all our decisions as AI engineers are governed by
一些传统软件工程师不太会遇到的约束
constraints that typically are applied less to software engineers,
比如单任务成本
which is like the cost per task,
这个成本会因为你使用的模型不同而大幅波动
which can swing a lot based on the model you use,
以及你采用的架构不同而变化
the architecture you use.
我们还要面对推理模型带来的延迟要求，以及其他一些我们可以调控的因素
We have latency requirements with reasoning models and other things that we can control.
当然，我们还必须保证一定的质量，并且在这里要格外注意数据隐私
We obviously have some quality to respect and data privacy in this case that we need to be careful of.
好在我们有一整套技术栈来帮我们
Fortunately, we have a stack to help us,
不管是从提示词工程
whether it is from prompt engineering,
到上下文工程、工具编排，或者搭建我们自己的评估系统
context engineering, to using tools orchestration or building our own evaluation systems,
我们喜欢把这一切看成某种自主性滑块，从非常简单的
and we like to see that as some sort of autonomy slider that goes from very simple just
只给模型写提示词，到构建完整的智能体系统
prompting a model to building agentic systems,
在这里，从简单提示到更复杂的工作流再到智能体系统，你加的复杂度越高
where the more you add complexity from prompting to more advanced workflows to agentic
系统的自主性就越强
systems, the more autonomy you add,
但你对整个系统的可控性也就越低
but also the less control you have over your whole system,
而且成本也会明显升高
and obviously the higher the cost.
对我们来说，在构建系统时做出合适选择非常重要……我们也会为客户做项目
And to us, that's very important to choose when we build for... we also build for clients,
所以我们会把自己在整个闭环里构建的东西整理出来进行教学
so that's why we try to teach what we build in all this loop,
但对我们来说，更重要的是搭建一个合适的系统，不要引入过多
but to us, it's really important to build the right system where we don't need too much
自主性，以免带来额外的问题和不确定性
autonomy, where it can add problems and uncertainty.
很明显，大多数人都对构建智能体很感兴趣
And obviously, most people are interested in building agents,
但我们客户想要的这些“智能体”，很多其实只是非常简单的
but most of these agents that our clients want are actually somewhat super simple
工作流，或者至少是我们可以很容易设计出来的工作流
workflows, or at least workflows that we can come up with pretty easily.
所以我想先从定义工作流开始，一直到多智能体系统
And so I want to try to start by defining workflows up to multi-agent systems,
最后用我们做的这个深度研究智能体的例子来收尾
finishing with this deep research example that we have made.
那么，什么是工作流
So what is a workflow?
工作流本身非常简单
A workflow is very simple.
它就是一个语言模型
It's just a language model,
但这是一个被增强过的模型，因为语言模型本身只会接收token和文本，然后生成
but augmented, mostly because language models just take in tokens and text and generate
token和文本，所以除了读写邮件之外，你其实很难只靠文本做太多事情
tokens and text, so you cannot do much with text other than reading and writing emails,
尽管我们当中有些人确实会做得更多
which some of us do more than that.
所以理想情况下，你会想在它之上加点东西
So ideally, you want to add stuff to it,
比如给它添加一些原本无法访问到的数据
like adding data that it may not have access to,
不管是你公司内部的数据，还是为了更好回答用户问题所需的其他数据
whether it's at your company or some other data that needs to best answer the user.
你可以给它接入各种工具，让它不只是生成token
You can give it access to tools to do other things than just generating tokens,
你还可以给它加上记忆，让它记住交互过程，从而更有用
and you can add a memory so that it can remember the interaction and be much more useful.
但即便如此，这还不是一个智能体
But still, this is not an agent,
它只是一个我们可以比较容易构建、而且相对可靠的东西
it's just a thing we can build easily that can be reliable.
而且工作流可以比这复杂得多
And a workflow can be even more complex than that.
你可以把多个提示词串联起来，在降低延迟和复杂度的同时完成更多事情
You can chain prompts together to reduce the latency and complexity to do many more things
并且基于严格的条件来控制流程
based on strict conditions.
你甚至可以用一个路由器/路由模块，根据条件自动决定
You can even do that with a router to decide automatically based on conditions on what you
接下来要做什么，是用一个更小的模型，还是先去执行另一个任务再回来
want to do, whether it is to use a smaller model or just do a different task and then come back.
你可以并行地做这些事情，以提高效率，或者通过多数投票
You can do that in parallel to be more efficient or to improve the results with majority
以及其他技术来提升结果质量
voting and other techniques.
你还可以加入循环，根据评判反馈自动改进结果
And you can even add loops to automatically improve the results based on a judge feedback.
但这一切仍然称不上是智能体
But all this is still not agentic,
它只是一个我们可以构建出来，并往里添加各种组件的工作流
it's just a workflow that we can build and add all these things.
我们甚至可以把这些工作流组合起来
We can even combine them,
构建出非常高级的工作流
we can build really advanced workflows.
那么，这样的东西什么时候才算变成一个智能体呢
So when does that thing become an agent?
这里我再次引用Anthropic的一个示意
And here again, I'm using an illustration from Anthropic.
这是一个我们非常认可的定义
It's a definition we really like.
当它需要采取行动时，更重要的是
It's just when it needs to take actions, and more importantly,
当它能够对环境中发生的事情做出反应时
when it can react to what happens in the environment.
简单来说，它应该能够自主采取行动，并对发生的事情做出反应
So very simply, it should be able to take autonomous action and react to what happens,
就像我刚才说的，并且还要能够
as I said, and be able,
理想情况下，能够进行规划，决定该用哪个工具，更重要的是
ideally, to plan to decide which tool to use, and more importantly,
决定不该用哪个工具
which tool not to use,
以及如何回应等等
how to respond, and everything.
那么我们什么时候该用这种东西
So when should we use this thing,
也就是智能体系统，而不是普通工作流呢
an agentic system, compared to a workflow?
一般来说，我们总是希望用最简单的方案
Well, typically, we always want to use the simplest solution.
如果只写一个提示词就能搞定，那是最理想的
If just a prompt works, that's ideal.
在我们真正开始构建东西的时候
And when we build things,
我们总是先从几个问题出发
we always try to start with questions,
然后结合我们那套自主性滑块来思考
and use our sort of autonomy slider.
所以我们可以先列出一串简单的问题，比如
So just a list of simple questions we can answer would be,
模型是否已经对要完成的任务有足够的了解
if the model already knows enough about the task to be done,
不管是用户在提问，还是其他类型的任务
whether it is a user asking a question or some other task,
那显然，你只要写个提示词让它去做就行
obviously, you can just prompt it and do it.
理想情况下，再加上一些示例
And ideally, add some examples,
也就是少样本示例
so a few-shot examples,
因为这确实能帮助模型进行适配
just because it really helps the model to adapt,
在运行时做一定程度的即时适应
somewhat adapt on the fly,
这都还只是简单的提示词使用
which would be just simple prompting.
接着，如果你需要外部上下文
Then, if you need external context,
如果这些内容不算太大，可以直接塞进提示词里
if it's not too big, and you can paste it in the prompt,
大概在二十万
under somewhat around 200,000
token以内，你就可以直接粘进去
tokens, you can just paste it right away,
最好是事先就准备好
and ideally, have it beforehand,
在用户提问之前就准备好
before your user asks it,
然后用上下文缓存
and use context caching,
这样效率会更高
so that it's more efficient,
比如说，只是回答关于同一份报告的几个问题
to just, for example, answer several questions about the same report,
或者针对同一套隐私文档
or the same your privacy documents,
或者你可能拥有的任何内部文档
or whatever internal documents you may have.
但如果这些上下文在用户向你的模型提问之前是未知的
Now, if the context is not known until the user asks a question to your model,
这时你就需要在运行时按需注入知识
this is where you may try to inject knowledge on the fly,
根据问题的内容来注入
based on the question,
不管是因为你的数据是私有的
whether it is because your data is private,
而你需要把这些信息检索出来才能回答这个问题
and you need to retrieve it to answer the question,
又或者如果这是模型尚未被训练到的最新内容
or if it's something recent that the models haven't been trained on,
或者是特定领域的内容你可能就需要注入额外知识
or domain-specific, you might want to inject knowledge.
如果你想用不同方式来完成所有这些事情
And if you want to do all this in different ways,
或者根据不同条件来决定怎么做
or depending on conditions,
这时你就会用到一种更高级的“工作流”
this is where you use a more advanced, quote-unquote, workflow,
也就是预先设定好的步骤和顺序
with predetermined steps and sequences.
实际上我们为一个客户构建的工作流示例是工单支持处理本质上
And so, in practice, an example of a workflow we built for a client was a support ticket handling, where, basically,
你总是会有相同的几个步骤
you have always the same steps,
按同样的顺序系统先接收到一条工单
in the same order, that the system receives a ticket,
然后对其进行分类并把它路由到正确的团队
it classifies it, routes it to the right team,
接着起草一份回复
it drafts a response,
再根据该团队的政策对回复进行校验
it can validate it against the policy of the team,
然后再把它发送出去
and then send it.
这里的关键在于这些步骤始终是相同的
And here, the key point is that these steps are always the same,
顺序也从不改变
the order never changes,
它总是需要按同样的顺序执行这六个步骤
it always needs to do these six steps in the same order,
因此如果把它做成一个智能体只会增加额外开销而不会带来额外价值
and so, building this as an agent would just add overhead without adding anything extra.
在这里你并不需要对任何东西进行动态响应
You don't need to dynamically react on anything here,
你只需要把这些步骤执行完就行
you just need to execute these steps.
所以在这种情况下使用工作流是非常合理的
So a workflow definitely makes sense in this case.
那么对于智能体你需要先问自己的是你的系统是否需要主动采取行动
So, for an agent, what you want to ask yourself is if your system needs to take actions,
或者是否需要能够进行动态分支决策
or to be able to branch dynamically.
比如说要不要调用不同的API
So, whether it is to call different APIs,
取决于用户的具体需求
depending on what the user needs,
要不要向数据库写入数据
or write to the database or not,
做不同的操作进行推理以及做其他事情
do different, do reasoning, and other things.
这时智能体就会变得有用
This is where an agent can be useful.
我们的一个案例是加拿大的一家CRM平台他们想为
And an example we had was a CRM platform in Canada that wanted to create a chatbot for
自己的CRM平台为他们的用户
their CRM platform, for their users,
也就是他们的客户提供一个可以自动生成营销内容的聊天机器人
their clients, to be able to generate marketing content automatically.
一开始他们联系到我们是因为他们在申请一个AI相关的资助项目
And initially, they reached out to us because they were applying to an AI grant,
他们想要一个多智能体系统用很多智能体来做各种不同的事情
and they wanted a multi-agent system to do a lot of different things with agents for
覆盖所有环节这听起来确实很符合这个以AI为重点的资助项目
everything, which did sound really well for the grant because it was like AI-focused,
但为了一个相对简单的营销聊天机器人去做那么多智能体其实非常大材小用
but it seemed really overkill to make many agents to do something quite simple as a marketing chatbot.
所以最后我们一如既往地会先努力搞清楚客户真正需要的是什么以及
So, in the end, what we always do is to try to really understand what the client needs and
他们想要的是什么而这两者往往是很不一样的
wants, which is oftentimes very different.
于是通过和他们的深入沟通
And so, by talking with them,
我们发现他们实际的工作流总是大同小异而且始终很简单
we figured that the actual workflow was always somewhat the same, always simple.
智能体只需要先制定一个计划来决定自己要做什么
The agent needed to make a plan to decide what it should do,
然后检索该客户特定的数据生成内容
then retrieve the data specific to the client, generate the content,
再对内容进行校验并在需要时进行修正
validate it, and fix it if needed.
所以这些任务始终是按顺序串行执行的
And so, the tasks were always sequential,
就是我们想做的那几个固定任务
the same few tasks that we wanted to do.
它们之间高度耦合
They were super coupled,
始终围绕生成营销内容这一件事
always the same thing about generating marketing content,
只是面向不同客户和不同内容形式而已
but just for different clients and for different formats.
而且整个序列都高度依赖上下文
And the whole sequence is context dependent.
不管是制定计划
So, whether it is the plan,
还是检索或生成
the retrieval, or generation,
或者修正都需要始终把当前内容放在脑子里才能尽可能生成最好的结果
or fix, it all needs to have the content in mind to be able to generate the best content as possible.
因此如果像客户最初设想的那样把决策拆分到不同智能体上
So, splitting decisions across different agents,
像客户所希望的那样
as the client wanted,
就会带来很多问题
would have caused a lot of issues,
无论是信息传递还是在工具调用等环节的交接错误
whether it is information or just handoff errors with tool calls and other things that
都会不断叠加从而降低系统的可靠性
would add, that would reduce reliability.
所以我们反过来只构建了一个智能体
So, instead, we just built one agent,
而是通过工具来扩展它的能力
but used tools as our capabilities.
这样做的好处非常明显
And this is really great,
因为每个工具都可以有自己的系统提示词
because with tools, they can have their own system prompt,
可以有自己的校验逻辑
they can have their own validation logic,
甚至可以使用各自独立的语言模型或独立的语言模型调用
even their own LLM or own LLM calls.
所以你可以用工具做非常多的事情
So, you can do tons of things with tools.
回到我们的这个案例
And from our example,
我们有一个专门的校验工具
we had a validation tool,
还有一个针对所有内容格式的专用工具
one tool specific to all formats,
比如短信工具或邮件工具
the SMS tool or email tool.
结果就是我们把工具当作各自领域的专家来用
And the result is that we use tools as specialists,
但全局上下文始终保留在这一个智能体内部
but the global context stays within our only agent,
也就是这个负责决策和规划的智能体
the decision maker and the planner.
但如果我们这样做就意味着所有东西都要留在智能体里
But if we do that, it means that everything stays within our agent.
因此我们会受到一个约束
So, we have a constraint,
就是这个智能体所用模型的上下文窗口
which is the context window of our agent,
也就是我们正在使用的模型的上下文窗口
of the model that we are using,
而这个上下文由很多部分组成
which is made of many things.
显然包括系统提示词
The system prompt, obviously,
我们给它的指令工具定义
the instructions that we give it, the tool definitions,
各种schema以及如何使用这些工具的说明
the different schemas and how to use these tools.
还有要完成任务的少样本示例
A few-shot examples of the task to be done.
这显然非常有用
It's really great, obviously,
用示例来“教学”
to teach by examples.
正如我们在模型上看到的那样
As we've seen with models,
对于大多数任务模型用这种方式能学得非常快
they learn very quickly that way for most tasks.
你还可以加入检索到的数据
You can have retrieved data,
具体取决于你想做什么
depending on what you want to do.
甚至可以包含完整的对话历史
And even entire conversation history,
如果这是一个聊天机器人或任何会随时间演化的智能体
if it's a chatbot or whatever type of agent that evolves over time.
所以所有这些内容会占用大量空间
So, all this can take up a lot of space,
这就带来了一个问题
which causes a problem,
因为当我们一步步往下执行这些步骤时
because as we go through each of these steps,
上下文会不断膨胀而性能会不断下降
the context grows and the performance degrades,
这就是我们所说的“上下文腐烂”
which we call context rot.
问题在于这种情况会远远早于真正触及上下文窗口上限之前就开始出现
And the problem is that this happens much before the actual context window limit of,
比如说哪怕窗口上限是一百万个token
like, one million tokens, for example.
在大约二十万之后情况就会迅速恶化
It worsens quite fast after,
大概二十万左右当然这个数字一直在变化
like, 200,000, or it keeps changing,
但目前大致是在二十万这个量级
but around 200,000 now.
这主要是因为“中间丢失”问题
And this is mostly because the lost in the middle problem,
我们在训练这些长上下文模型时为了让它们能处理长上下文
where we basically teach these long context models to be able to handle long context by
会给它们喂入大量语料库
feeding them a large corpus,
在其中插入一条随机事实
inserting a random fact in them,
然后再把那条事实检索出来
and retrieving that fact.
所以这本质上更像是检索某个特定信息
So it's basically more retrieval of one specific thing,
但这并没有教会这些模型利用整本书
but it doesn't teach those models to leverage the whole book,
利用完整上下文来回答问题
the whole context, to answer the question.
所以这显然并不理想
So it's definitely not ideal,
但要构建这种大型数据集成本会非常高
but it would be too expensive to build this kind of large data set.
因此这种训练方式带来了一个问题就是我们必须管理这个上下文
So this way of training them caused the problem of us having to manage this context
预算也就是说要尽量让上下文保持精简且高度相关
budget, which means to always keep the context as lean and relevant as possible,
既要在token数量上降低成本
both to reduce cost in terms of token amount,
也要提升我们所使用的各项指标
but also to improve the metrics that we are using.
为此我们可以使用很多技术手段
And we can use many techniques for that.
我们可以裁剪内容
We can trim the content,
可以对其进行总结也可以基于特定条件进行检索
we can summarize it, we can retrieve based on criteria.
或者还可以使用Claude Code中/compact命令里的许多有趣技术
Or there are also many interesting techniques in the Claude Code /compact command
我建议大家去了解一下
that I recommend looking into.
这些都非常强大但在这次分享中我最感兴趣的是我们可以进行的委派
Really powerful ones. But the one I'm most interested in for this talk is the delegation that we can do to
把任务委派给具有自己上下文的工具或子智能体
either tools or subagents with their own context,
这也是我们使用的大多数框架正在做的事情
which is what most frameworks that we use are doing.
这就把我们引向了多智能体系统
And so this leads us to the multi-agent systems,
当我们拥有过多上下文时基本上就希望使用它们
where we basically want to use them when we have too much of this context,
比如说有二十多个工具时
mostly, like over 20 tools,
或者上下文本身变得过于庞大时
or just the context becomes way too large,
我们就可以把任务委派给工具或智能体
we can delegate to tools or to agents.
当然也可能有其他原因
And there can be other reasons,
比如你需要进行自主决策
like if you need to make autonomous decision making,
或者你需要工具多样性
or you need tool variability,
又或者是出于安全合规的考虑
or just security compliance,
比如你需要在某家医院内部本地部署一个智能体
if you need to have one agent locally inside one hospital,
比如说我之前就在医疗行业工作
for example, because I was in the healthcare field before,
当时我们所有东西都必须本地化部署
and we used to have everything local.
所以这也可以成为采用多智能体的一个理由
So that can be a reason for multi-agents.
那我为什么要讲这些呢
And why am I talking about all this?
因为我们发现AI产品从来不是只构建一个智能体或者只构建
Because what we've seen is that AI products are never just you build an agent or you build
一个多智能体的CrewAI之类的东西
a multi-agent CrewAI thing.
它们基本上都会把这些全部组合起来
They basically combine all of that.
它们会把工具和工作流结合在一起
They combine tools, workflows,
有些部分非常具体且预先定义好
some parts are more specific and predefined,
有些部分则更具灵活性
some parts have more flexibility.
我们认为AI工程师需要理解所有这些内容才能构建复杂系统
And we believe that AI engineers need to understand all these to build complex systems.
而深度研究智能体实际上就实现了这一点
And deep research actually implement that.
它是一个完整系统的非常好的示例
It's a very good example of a complete system,
因为它们整合了所有这些技术
since they integrate all of these techniques.
在展示我们如何构建自己的系统并让你们也能使用之前
And before we show how we built our own and allow you to use it as well,
我先快速介绍一下深度研究系统到底是什么以防有人不熟悉
let me just cover quickly what the deep research system is, just in case.
它是一个会规划自己需要研究内容的推理系统
It's a reasoning system that will plan what it needs to research about.
它在决定研究什么方面具有一定自主性
It has some autonomy to decide what to research about.
它拥有工具以及互联网或网页访问能力
It has tools, internet or web access.
它是可靠的会引用自己的信息来源
It's reliable, it will cite its sources.
它内部有自我反馈循环
It has feedback loops with itself,
也会与人类进行交互以获取人类反馈
but also with the human for human feedback.
所以正如我们所见这要智能体化得多
So this is much more agentic, as we see.
它运行的环境通常是网页用户提供的资料或者简单的API访问
It evolves in an environment which is typically the web or user-provided sources or just API access.
它是目标驱动的只有一个核心目标
And it's goal-driven. It has one objective.
我们不会精确告诉它要如何完成
We don't tell it how to do it exactly.
我们只会告诉它去研究某个主题
We just tell it do a research about something.
因此它通常远不止是一个聊天机器人
So it's typically much more than just a chatbot.
它本质上是在替代一个会对特定主题进行非常深入研究的人
It basically replaces someone that would do a very thorough research about a specific topic.
它会规划会搜索
It plans, it searches,
会检查会转向会综合信息并且可以反复迭代
it inspects, pivots, it synthesizes information and can iterate.
所以深度研究系统确实是
So deep research systems are really,
在我们看来用来学习如何构建这种复杂端到端系统的最佳项目之一
to us, one of the best projects to learn how to build such a complex end-to-end system.
因此我们决定构建我们自己的系统
So we decided to build our own.
在我们的案例中这个系统本质上是一个从某个主题出发端到端生成技术文章的系统
And in this case, our own is basically an end-to-end technical article production from a
因为在我们的业务中我们要制作课程课件
topic because we create course lessons in our case.
所以这个项目是出于真实业务需求而诞生的
So it came out of real utility,
这点是最重要的
which is the most important part.
因此这里的目标是拿到一个主题
So the goal here is to take a topic,
对其进行深入研究
research deeply about it,
并撰写一篇非常优秀的技术文章其中包含实际可运行的代码集成
and write a very good technical article with code integration that is actually runnable
以及真正有用的配图
with images that is useful,
而不是整篇文章都用随机生成的图片
not just randomly generated images throughout.
在实现这一点时会遇到一些挑战
And there are a few challenges when doing this.
首先在做研究时你需要非常高的精确率和召回率因为你
First, you need a really high precision and recall when doing the research because you
需要尽可能多的相关信息来源
need as much relevant sources as possible,
但又不能太多因为存在上下文长度受限的问题
but you don't need too much of them because of the limited context problem.
你需要减少幻觉和AI烂文/AI糟粕内容
You need to reduce hallucinations and AI slop,
这是显然的并且要融入大量人类反馈
obviously, and incorporate a lot of human feedback,
尤其是在写作环节
especially in the writing aspect.
一如我们在所有项目中所做的那样
And as we always do with projects,
我也认为你们都应该这样做
and I think you all should do as well,
我们一开始会先问自己一系列问题以更好地理解应该如何去做
we started this with asking ourselves questions to better understand how we should do it
以及我们是否真的应该去做
and if we should do it at all.
第一个问题是这件事值得做吗
The first question is, is this worthwhile?
是否已经存在我们之外可以直接使用的解决方案
Is there a solution outside of what we could build that already exists?
我们的分析是高质量技术内容的生产成本非常高
So our analysis is that high quality technical content is expensive to produce.
我们每天都在做这件事需要很多人投入也需要大量时间和审稿并且
We do that every day and we need a lot of people and it needs a lot of time and review and
这实在是非常耗时
it's just really time consuming,
成本也非常高尤其是因为这些人需要是相对资深的AI工程师
really expensive, especially because these people need to be somewhat senior AI engineers
才能讲清楚任何AI工程相关内容
to be able to explain anything in AI engineering.
所以他们需要具备专业知识
So they need expertise,
但他们是在教别人而不是在构建一个成功的产品
but to teach someone not to build a successful product.
因此成本高但并不那么赚钱
So it's expensive and not that lucrative.
所以没错理想状态是把这套流程的大部分自动化
So yeah, it would be ideal to automate most of this process.
正如我所说研究部分需要很强的召回率和精确率
As I said, the research needs strong recall and precision.
而在另一端
And on the other side,
写作部分则需要更受约束
the writing needs to be more constrained.
它需要避免幻觉
It needs to avoid hallucinations,
保持高质量并遵循你的语气或你想要的写作风格
be of high quality, follow your tone or the writing tone that you want,
以及你想要的结构
the structure that you want.
就深度研究工具而言
And in terms of deep research tools,
我们几乎每天都会用到所有这些工具，而且它们实在过于详尽
we use all of them pretty much daily and they are way too exhaustive.
它们收集了过多内容，而且噪音非常多
They gather way too much content and they have a lot of noise.
对于我们的使用场景来说并不理想
It's not ideal for us in our case.
我们确实会用这些工具，但还是决定自己搭一个，这样才能完全按我们的想法来做
We do use them, but we decided to build our own just to be able to do exactly what we wanted.
所以我们的决定是的
So the decision is, yes,
这件事是值得做的
that this was worthwhile,
但主要是作为对写作者的增强
but especially as a writer augmentation,
而不是取代他们
not to replace them.
因为正如我们所看到的
Because as we've seen,
即使你在当下打造出可以说是最好的系统
even if you do as... if you build the best system possible these days,
你依然很难创作出一篇内容
it's really hard to create a piece of content,
不管是视频还是文字课程
whether it is a video or a written lesson,
真正能与读者或观众产生共鸣的内容
that connects with the reader or the viewer.
你确实需要人的那种感觉，这样内容才能让某个人觉得有共鸣
You really need a human touch to be... so that it's relatable to someone.
你需要讲笑话
You need to make jokes,
要讲好笑的笑话，而不是老是重复同样的梗
good jokes, not the same ones all the time.
而且要和语境相契合
And the ones that are appropriate to the context.
所以要把这一切完全自动化是非常难的，我们也希望在这里始终保留人类参与
So it was... it's really difficult to automate all this and we want to keep a human in the loop there.
接下来我们问自己的第一个实际问题是
Now, the first actual question we ask ourselves is,
架构应该是什么样的
what should be the architecture?
它应该是一个智能体
If it should be an agent,
多个智能体，还是一个工作流
multiple agents, a workflow?
我们的分析是
And the analysis here is that,
首先，研究这一部分本身非常探索性
first, we have the research part that is really exploratory.
它需要找到大量信息来源
It needs to find lots of sources.
它需要在网上不断探索，在缺少信息时弄清楚自己还需要找到什么
It needs to explore the web to understand what it needs to find if it misses information.
所以它需要具备迭代能力
So it needs to be able to iterate,
能够转向、重新搜索
to pivot, to search again.
它需要很大的灵活性
It needs a lot of flexibility.
而在另一边
And on the other side,
写作智能体则要确定性强得多
the writing agent is much more deterministic.
它需要遵循特定的语气
It needs to follow a specific tone,
遵循特定结构
to follow a structure,
总之，它需要的约束远多于灵活性
to... yeah, it needs to be much more constrained than it needs flexibility.
你不希望出现这种AI烂文
You don't want this AI slope.
你不希望出现那些特定的烂词、套话句子
You don't want specific words, specific sentences.
你希望的是特定的句式和特定的格式
You want specific sentences and specific formats.
所以它的约束要严格得多
So it's much more constrained.
因此我们这里存在一个冲突：研究需要灵活性
So we have a conflict here where the research needs flexibility,
但写作需要约束
but the writing needs constraint.
所以我们的决定是把它拆成两个系统
And so the decision is to split into two systems,
一个是更偏探索、更动态、更智能体化的研究智能体
the research agent that is more exploratory, dynamic, more agentic,
另一个是写作智能体
and the writer agent,
也就是更具确定性和一致性的写作系统
the writer system that is more deterministic and consistent.
像这样的问题我们有一大堆
And we have tons of these questions,
在课程里我们会详细展示如何构建这两个系统
and we show in our course exactly how to build these two systems.
但在这里我们只有两个小时
But here it's just two hours,
所以会更多地聚焦在研究智能体上
so we focus on the research agent a bit more,
尤其是在接下来的几个问题中
especially for the next few questions.
那么这里的问题是，它应该如何被创建
So here, how should it be created?
也就是研究智能体应该如何与写作工作流、写作步骤进行沟通
Well, how should the research agent communicate with the writer workflow, the writer step?
在测试之后，我们在这方面转向了好几次
Well, we pivoted a few times after testing it,
而这其实是最重要的部分
and that's the most important part,
就是你自己要真正使用你的产品，或者让潜在用户来用你的产品，从而给你
is to actually use your product or a potential user should use your product to give you
尽可能早地提供反馈
feedback as early on as possible.
就我们这边来说，我们用它来搭建课程，再用课程来用它
And on our end, we used it to build a course to use it,
这样一来，我们就很容易迭代，也很容易把学到和做到的东西教出去
so it was really easy to iterate and to teach what we learned and what we did.
我们发现的是，我们的用户
And what we saw is that our users,
也就是我自己和团队
which were myself and the team,
发现我们要么同时用上两个智能体，要么干脆不用这个系统
saw that we always used either both agents or we didn't use a system.
所以我们并不是简单地先用研究，再切到写作这样来回切换
So we weren't just alternating between the research and then the writer.
如果我们要切换
If we were to alternate,
也只是最后再用写作智能体来添加一些新的建议
it was just with the writer at the end to add new suggestions,
新的主题、新的信息，用来给文章增删内容
new topics, new information to add to the article or to remove to it,
但研究部分通常在这之前就已经做得相当完善了
but the research was already quite perfect and done beforehand,
稍后你会在萨姆里迪的部分看到这一点
as you will see with Samriddhi.
如果需要大的改动
And if a big change was needed,
我们就会直接把整个流程重新跑一遍
we just would rerun the process again.
所以我们并不需要一套复杂的编排机制
So we didn't need to have proper orchestration in place.
而且这两个智能体是基于同一批产物来工作的
And the two agents work on the same artifacts.
研究智能体会生成一个research.md文件，把所有研究内容做成总结，然后把它
The research agent produced a research.md file with all its research summarized and sent
发送给写作智能体
it to the writer.
因此它们需要有一种彼此沟通的方式
So they need to have ways to communicate together.
所以我们做出的决定是把两个智能体分开，在没有编排系统的情况下顺序运行
So the decision that we made is to separate the two agents and run them sequentially without orchestration,
也就是说只用一个脚本，一个非常基础的脚本
so just a script, just a very basic script.
而且我们的两个智能体放在同一个项目里
And our two agents are in the same project,
这样更容易维护
so that it's easier to maintain,
同时它们共享一些专用文件
but also they share dedicated files,
这样它们之间的沟通就很方便
so it's easy to have them communicate with each other,
也方便它们通过这些文件与我们沟通
but also have them communicate with us through these files.
把它们放在同一个项目里，对用Claude Code之类做AI辅助编程也很有帮助
And having them together in the same project is useful for AI-assisted coding with Claude
不管你用的是哪种系统
code or whatever system you are using.
关于研究智能体的下一个问题是：它应该如何行为
The next question for the research agent is how should it behave?
所以我们非常想搞清楚，我们希望从这个研究助手中得到的流程到底是什么样
So we really wanted to understand what would be the process that we would want out of this
在真正构建它之前就要想明白
research assistant before building it.
同样地，我们在测试之后又对其进行了打磨
And again, we refined this after testing,
最终我们发现自己非常需要一份写得很好的人工指南
and in the end we really needed a good human written guideline,
这份指南基本上要写清楚主题是什么、我在这节课里想覆盖的所有内容
which would basically be just what is the topic about anything I'm interested in covering
以及我们认为相关的有用链接
in this lesson, and useful links that we think are relevant.
有时我会把某些特定主题的AI通讯发给它
Sometimes I send the AI newsletter on some specific topics,
有时是我自己的视频，或者我们之前讲过的其他主题
sometimes it's my own videos or other topics that we covered.
我们发现，显然这里会有创作者偏见
And we saw that, obviously there's a creator bias here,
但我们发现，在指南中把智能体的目标定义得越清晰
but we saw that the more we define the agent's goal in the guideline,
也就是给它的自由度越小
so the less freedom it had,
产出的效果就越好
the better the results were.
另外，如果我们在发给智能体的指南里附上链接
Then if we give links in that guideline we send to the agent,
智能体就需要去抓取网页内容
the agent needs to scrape web pages,
需要能够消化YouTube视频
needs to be able to digest YouTube videos,
以及GitHub代码仓库，即便这些仓库对用户来说是私有的
GitHub repositories, even if they are private to the user,
给我自己，用来收集所有必要的上下文
to myself, to gather all the necessary context.
然后在那之后它需要真正开始执行深度研究这件事
And then after that it needs to do its actual deep research thing,
也就是在网上搜索任何缺失且需要理解的内容
so search the web for anything that is missing and needs understanding,
然后整理和修订所有这些上下文，把它写成一个非常好的最终成果，它将会
and then revise all this context and write that into a very nice final artifact that will
被发送给写作智能体
be sent to the writer agent.
那么我们是如何做到这一切的
So how did we do all that?
我们是如何抓取我们提供链接的网页内容并进行网页搜索的
How did we scrape web content that we give the links to and do web searches?
一如既往，我们会简化问题，而不是重复造轮子
Well we, as always, simplify the problem and don't reinvent the wheel.
我们使用现有的东西
We use existing things,
现有的系统和API
existing systems and APIs,
并把问题拆分成更简单的小问题
and divide the problem into simpler problems.
所以首先，在抓取方案上
So first, scraping solution,
我们使用 Firecrawl 和智能体式抓取
we use Firecrawl and agentic scraping,
出于很多原因，Sam 会在讲研究智能体时进一步展开
and this is for many reasons that Sam will talk a bit more about the research agents,
所以我在这里就不多展开
so I won't cover it too much,
但这种抓取方式对更动态的网站以及其他
but it's really useful to have this kind of scraping for more dynamic websites and other
会阻止抓取的那类网站非常有用
types of websites that can block scraping.
而在网页搜索方面，我们曾经使用
And for web searches we used,
以前使用的是 Perplexity
we used to use perplexity,
现在则使用带 grounding 的 Gemini
now Gemini with grounding,
以便直接获得带来源的精确答案
to get precise answers with sources directly,
如有需要，我们之后还可以对这些来源进行抓取
which we can then scrape if we need to,
否则我们已经可以通过良好的提示，从这次 grounding 查询中获得想要的信息
but otherwise we can already prompt it well enough to get the information we want from this grounding query.
接下来是 YouTube 视频
Now for YouTube videos,
因为 YouTube 上有大量优质信息
because there are a lot of great information on YouTube,
理想情况下我们只想把文本传给智能体
we want to ideally pass just the text to the agent,
因为视频本身很重
because the video is quite heavy,
我们尝试了很多方法
and we tried a lot of things,
但通常你需要先下载视频再提取字幕文本
but typically you need to download the video and extract the transcript,
不过幸运的是，现在 Gemini 可以直接通过一个 YouTube 链接来处理这一切
but fortunately Gemini now handles this directly with a YouTube URL,
你只需要提供 YouTube 链接并就此提问
you just give the YouTube URL and ask questions about it,
甚至可以直接让它提供字幕文本
or even ask to provide the transcript,
所以这非常有用
so it's very useful.
很显然，我们决定采用这种方式
We decided to use that, obviously.
然后是 GitHub 内容
And now for the GitHub content,
我们只是使用 gitingest 库把指定内容拉取成 Markdown
we just used the gitingest library to get a specific content into Markdown,
并且可以给它提供一个 token 来访问我们的私有代码仓库
and we can provide it with a token to access our private repositories.
所以这其实非常简单
So it's really simple,
你会在代码仓库里看到这一点
and you will see that in the repository.
在框架方面，我们使用了 MCP 搭配 FastMCP
For framework, we used MCP with FastMCP,
这样我们就能为不同流程提供相应的工具
so that we can have tools for the different processes,
而且我们可以通过一个 MCP 提示词，大致给出要做什么以及如何使用
and we can have an MCP prompt to basically give a recipe on what to do and how to use the
这些工具的“配方”给智能体，这非常有用
tools to the agent, which is very useful.
接下来一个半小时里我们会深入讲解这一点
We will talk in depth about that in the next hour and a half.
然后在研究部分
Then for the research,
在环境搭建上，我们基本只用了 Python
the setup, we basically just used Python,
用 UV 管理依赖，还有 GitHub，这当然少不了
UV for managing dependencies, and GitHub, obviously.
在模型方面，我们最近把所有部分都切换成了 Gemini
And for the models, we recently changed for everything to be Gemini,
主要是因为我刚才提到的 YouTube 能力
mostly because of the YouTube thing that I mentioned,
但我们也发现它首先表现得非常好
but also we saw that first it works really well,
而且我们可以在 Pro 和 Flash 之间切换
and we can alternate between Pro and Flash,
即更便宜和更昂贵的那个
the cheaper one and more expensive,
取决于任务的复杂度
depending on the complexity of the task.
所以我们在代码中交替使用它们
So we use them alternatively in the code.
还有一点我们非常喜欢的是，它为我们的学生提供了免费额度
And the one thing that we really like is also that it has a free tier for our students,
所以对我们来说非常方便
so it's really convenient for us.
但显然，我们也拿它和其他模型做了对比
But obviously, we also compared to the other models.
之前我们使用的是 Claude Opus
We were using Claude Opus before,
以及其他 Claude 模型
and other Claude models,
甚至还有 OpenAI 的模型，但我们发现 Gemini 要有趣得多
and even OpenAIs, but we've seen that Gemini is much more interesting,
尤其是和如今的 OpenAI 模型相比
especially from OpenAI these days.
所以我们现在使用 Gemini
So we are using Gemini,
但你仍然需要和不同模型对比，以确保自己用的是合适的那个
but you need to compare with different models to be sure that you are using the right one.
最后，在更偏理论的部分
And finally, for the more theory part,
研究智能体是如何与用户进行沟通的
how does the research agent communicate with the user?
这一切都在 MCP 提示词内部完成
It's inside the MCP prompt.
我们设计了特定步骤来暂停并与用户交互
We have specific steps to stop and interact with the users.
而所有这些交互都是通过文件来处理的
And all these interactions are handled through files,
无论是指南、研究文件，还是保罗将在写作者部分谈到的其他文件
whether it is the guideline or the research file or other files that Paul will talk about in the writer part.
顺便说一句，我提到的所有内容以及更多内容，都整理在一份类似速查表的东西里
And by the way, everything I mentioned and much more is in some sort of cheat sheet that
我们也在代码仓库的 readme 里附上了链接
we also linked in the readme of the repository,
所以你完全可以免费访问
so you can definitely access it for free,
很显然，它在 GitHub 上
obviously, it's on GitHub.
接下来就是我们讲解深度研究的部分
And now is the part where we talk about the deep research,
如果你还没获取代码仓库，可以现在扫一下二维码
so you can scan the code if you haven't to get the repository,
接下来由萨姆里迪接棒
and Samriddhi will take over.
抱歉各位，请给我一分钟
Sorry, everyone. Just give me one minute.
好，那我来讲深度研究智能体
Awesome. So I'll be talking about the deep research agent.
那么，什么是深度研究智能体
And so what is a deep research agent?
正如路易已经解释过的
As Louis already explained,
它可以通过搜索网络来检索任何主题
that it can search any topic by searching the web.
它可以分析 YouTube 视频
It can analyze YouTube videos.
最终它会给你一份带引用来源的报告
And finally, it will give you a cited report.
在构建方式上，我们为此使用了 MCP
How we've built it, we've used MCP for this,
它是一个为智能体提供工具和数据访问能力的开放标准
which is an open standard for giving agents access to tools and data.
这里的关键理念、设计选择是：智能体是负责完成所有
The key idea, like the design choice here is that the agent is the brain that is doing all
推理的“大脑”，正如路易强调的那样
of the reasoning, as Louis highlighted,
研究环节中任何存在的空白，都是由智能体来填补
that any gaps that are there in the research part is being done by the agent.
它会思考研究中是否有缺失
It thinks if there's anything missing in the research,
是否需要运行多轮研究
if it needs to run multiple researches,
或者是否必须去搜索别的内容
or it has to search something else,
这些都是由智能体来完成的部分
that is the part that is being done by the agent,
而服务器，也就是 MCP
whereas the server, the MCP,
则负责处理所有能力层面的东西
is handling all of the capabilities.
它会对外暴露所有工具
So it's going to be exposing all of the tools,
也会暴露可用的资源和提示词
it's going to be exposing the resources and the prompts that are there.
我们使用了一个叫 FastMCP 的东西
We've used something called FastMCP,
它是一个能让创建智能体变得非常容易的库
which is a library that really makes creation of agents very easy.
所以它把所有复杂性都封装了起来
So it hides all of the complexities,
而且你完全不需要为智能体之间编写任何协议或任何形式的通信内容
and you do not have to write any sort of protocols or any sort of communications between agents.
这些全部都由 FastMCP 来处理
All of that is handled by FastMCP.
我们使用 Claude Code 作为我们的智能体运行框架
And we're using Claude Code as our agent harness.
但这份代码本身与它是解耦独立的
But this code is independent of that.
如果你更倾向于使用 Cursor 或 GitHub Copilot
If you're more inclined towards using Cursor or GitHub Copilot,
你可以把 Claude Code 换成你喜欢的任何其他智能体运行框架
you can swap Claude Code with any other agent harness that you like.
接下来我会讲这三样东西
So I'll be talking about these three things.
一个 MCP 服务器会暴露工具、提示词和资源
An MCP server exposes tools, prompts, and resources.
那什么是工具呢
So what are tools?
工具基本上就是智能体可以执行的所有动作
Tools are basically all of the actions an agent can take.
比如深度研究，或者去做 Google 搜索
So deep research, or going and doing Google search,
或者分析一个视频并给我们生成字幕稿
or analyzing a video and giving us a transcript,
又或者整理汇总成一份报告
or compiling a report.
所有这些动作类的事情都是通过工具完成的
So all of these action things are done by tools.
而 MCP 暴露的第二个东西是提示词
Whereas the second thing that the MCP exposes is prompt,
本质上就是指令
which is basically instruction.
你知道的，当你在和聊天界面对话时
You know, when you're talking to chat,
你会给它一些指令
you give it instruction.
在这里，就是智能体可以遵循的这些提示词
So this, in case, is prompts that the agent can follow.
在我们的例子里，我们有一个详细的提示词，稍后我会连同代码一起给你看
And in our case, we have a detailed prompt that I'll show you in a minute with the code.
最后第三个东西是资源
And finally, the third thing is resources,
也就是智能体可以读取的数据
which is the data the agent can read.
这些更像是静态数据
So this is like static data,
比如我们正在使用的模型名称
which is the model names we're using,
以及我们所用的各种版本信息
the sort of versions that we have.
还有我们配置的各种功能开关
We have any sort of feature flags.
这些都属于资源的一部分
Those are all part of the resources.
所以这些是智能体可以读取的内容
So these are something that the agent can read.
这里不会发生任何动作执行
There is no action being done here.
在工具方面，我们一共定义了三个工具
In terms of tools, we have three tools.
第一个是深度研究工具
So first is the deep research tool.
深度研究工具基本上会做的事情是
The deep research tool basically does,
比如去做 Google 搜索，并为我们提供所有内容对应的来源
you know, Google search and give us sources for everything that we have.
它会为我们提出的任何查询提供答案
So it provides us with answers for any sort of query we had, we have.
同时也会把所有对应的来源一并给出
And also it provides us all of the sources of that.
所以在这里我们使用的是 Gemini API
So this is... we're using Gemini API for this.
第二个工具是分析 YouTube 视频的工具
The second tool that we have is the analyze YouTube video tool.
这个工具同样也是使用 Gemini API
For this as well, we're using the Gemini API.
你可以拿任意一个 YouTube 链接
So you can take any YouTube URL and,
把它粘贴进来，它就会在这里给你生成字幕稿
you know, paste it, and it's gonna give you a transcript here.
最后我们还有一个汇总研究结果的工具
And finally, we have the compile research tool.
它基本上会把前两个工具的输出结果汇总整理起来
So what... it basically compiles the output of the previous two tools.
等我给你看代码的时候，我们会更详细地讲 .memory 文件以及它的细节
So we're gonna be talking more about the .memory file and the details of that when I
给你展示代码的时候会讲到这些
show you the code.
所以我刚刚讲的是
So I just talked about,
工具的各个组成部分
you know, the parts of the tool,
以及我们这个智能体的构成
the agent that we have.
但更大的层面上，这是整体架构
But, you know, this is the overall architecture.
我们使用 Claude Code 作为 MCP 客户端
So we are using Claude Code as MCP client.
这里特别强调一下
Just to highlight here,
对我们来说 Claude Code 既是
Claude Code for us is both,
MCP 客户端，又是一个大语言模型
you know, MCP client and an LLM.
所以你可以把它理解成我们在用的大脑
So, you know, it is like the brain which is being used.
同时它又是 MCP 客户端
Also, it is MCP client,
负责和我们这边的 MCP 服务器进行通信
which is talking to the MCP server that we have.
我们的 Fast MCP 服务器里面包含工具、资源和提示词
The fast MCP server that we have has tools, resources, and prompts.
这里是我们每个工具的详细信息
These are the details about each of the tools that we have.
所以所有这些
So all of these, you know,
工具——前两个工具会把内容写入一个叫 .memory 的文件夹
tools... the first two tools write to a folder called .memory.
本质上我们是希望有个地方，可以
And basically, we wanted something... we wanted to,
把所有这些结果都保存下来
like, preserve all of this,
因为这样更方便做日志记录
because it is easier for logging,
也更方便我们去核查拿到的所有结果
it is easier for us to verify all of the results that we're getting.
所以我们会把所有结果都写入到一个文件夹里
So, you know, we are writing down all of our results to a folder.
而第三个工具会从这个文件夹中读取内容，并为我们生成一个文件
And the third tool reads from this folder and creates a file for us.
也就是一个研究结果的 markdown 文件，叫做 research.md
So a research... a markdown file called research.md.
前两个工具会向 Gemini API 发起调用
The first two tools do API calls to Gemini API.
最终所有东西都会
And finally, everything is,
被读写到这个特定的文件夹里
like, you know, read and written to this particular folder.
接下来我会给你展示代码
So now I'm gonna show you the code.
好的，这是我们这个……我先把页面放大一点
Okay. So this is how the... let me just zoom a bit.
不好意思，好，现在正好，你可以看到这是我们代码的整体结构
Sorry. Okay. Perfect. So, you know, this is how we have structured our code.
你不用被这些东西吓到
You know, you don't have to get intimidated by this.
我们会把它讲得非常简单
So we're gonna simplify it a lot.
这里是两个主要的文件夹
So, you know, these are the main two folders.
一个是 research 文件夹，一个是 writing 文件夹
The research folder and the writing folder.
保罗会讲写作这一部分
Paul is gonna be talking about the writing part.
我这边只讲研究这一部分
I'll just go and talk about the research part.
如果你还记得，我在演讲一开始的时候
So if you remember, when I started my presentation,
讲的第一件事就是 MCP 服务器
the first thing I talked about was the MCP server.
这里就是我这边的 MCP 服务器文件
So, you know, this is the MCP server file that I have.
接着我……你可以看到
And then I... so, you know,
这是我们如何搭建 MCP 服务器的
this is how you set up the MCP server.
我们在这里加载了一些配置
So we have some settings that we are loading up here.
基本上就是我们所用模型的名称
So these are basically the name of the models that we have.
我一会儿可以给你看
I can show that to you in a minute.
然后你可以看到这是我们如何初始化服务器的
And, you know, this is how you set up the server.
你需要给它一个名称和一个版本号
So you give it a name and a version.
然后你要注册三样东西
And then you register three things.
这一点你需要记住
So, you know, this is something that you should remember.
我们注册的是工具、资源和提示词
We're registering tools, resources, and prompts.
接着我们在这里配置了一些基础日志
And then we're just setting up basic logging here.
我们还使用了一个叫 Opik 的东西来做可观测性
And we're using something called Opik for observability.
这一块保罗会待会儿详细讲
And Paul is gonna be talking more in detail about that.
然后最后我们就真正创建了这个 MCP 服务器
And then we're finally creating the MCP server, you know.
现在我们来看一下是如何注册这些工具的
And now let's see how we have registered the tools.
如果我们打开这个叫 tools 的文件
So if we go to this file called tools,
也就是这个 Python 的 tools 文件
the Python tools file,
你可以看到我们是这样注册这些工具的
this is how we have registered the tools.
所以在把这些工具注册到……
So for registering the tools with,
你知道的，Fast MCP……啊不，对，是在注册工具时
you know, fast MCP... sorry, for registering tools,
你需要三样东西
you need three things.
第一样当然是
The first thing is, of course,
工具的名称
the name of the tool.
所以在这里，这个工具的名字是 DeepResearch
So here, the name of the tool is DeepResearch.
第二样是参数
The second thing is arguments.
我们会给它传入两个参数
So we're passing it two arguments.
第一个是工作目录
The first one is the working directory.
第二个是我们要问它的问题或查询
And the second is the question or the query that we're gonna be asking it.
然后你需要一个关于你的工具要做什么的定义
Then you need a definition for what your tool is gonna be doing.
所以你在写这个定义时要尽可能精确
So, you know, you have to be as precise as possible when you're writing this definition.
最后，我们还要对已有的这些参数做出定义
And finally, we also have the definition for the arguments that we have.
所以，你看，这就是你编写这个工具的方式
So, you know, so this is the way you write the tool.
接着我们就有用于可观测性的代码
Then we just have the code for the observability.
然后最后是实现部分
And then finally, we have the implementation.
我们会返回这个工具的实现
We're returning the implementation for the tool.
就是这样
So this is it.
所以，你看，这就是你定义一个工具的方式
So, you know, this is how you define a tool.
这里没有什么复杂的地方
And there's no complications here.
但我们来更详细地看一下这个工具本身
But let's go into a little bit more detail about the tool itself.
也就是这个工具是如何工作的
So how this tool is working.
对于 DeepResearch 这个工具
So for the DeepResearch tool,
基本上在第一步
we are basically in the first step,
我们只是对所有路径做校验
we're just validating all of our parts.
我们会检查自己是不是在当前目录下
So we're checking if we're in the current directory or not.
其次，我们要确保我们要写入的那个内存文件
And secondly, we are ensuring that the memory file that we're writing to,
本质上就是我们把所有结果写进去的那个文件夹
basically it's a folder where we're writing all our results to,
是否已经存在
if it exists or not.
这些校验都会在这里完成
And we do all of this validation here.
然后我们会对已有的查询运行这个 grounded search
And then, you know, we run this grounded search on the query that we have.
一旦拿到这个查询的结果
Once we get the result of this query,
我们会返回状态
we return the status.
比如是否成功
If it's successful or not.
我们发出的查询是什么
What was the query that we sent?
我们得到的答案是什么
What is the answer that we get?
所以我们会得到一个详细的响应
So we get a detailed response.
这对我们团队调试以及梳理所有数据非常有帮助
And this has been very helpful for our team to debug and go through all of the data that
这样我们就能不断打磨已有的研究结果
we get so that we can refine the research results we have.
接下来更详细地说一下我们是如何
Going into more detail about how we are,
运行这项研究的，对吧
you know, running the research, right?
如果你看这里，我们有一个 run grounded search 函数
So if you see this, the run grounded search function that we have,
里面有一个我们已经写好的提示词
we have a prompt that we've already written.
你点进来就能看到我们用的研究提示词
So if you go here, you can see the research prompt that we have.
里面大致是在说，如果你有任何问题
So we're basically saying that if you have any questions,
你必须对这个问题给出一个详细且全面的回答
you have to provide a detailed comprehensive answer to the question that is there.
要重点参考官方和权威来源
Focus on the official authoritative references and,
并尽可能包含所有相关细节
you know, make sure you're including all the relevant details as possible.
而且要清晰地标注你的信息来源
And make sure to cite your sources clearly.
所以，这就是我们在 deep research 工具里使用的提示词
So, you know, this is the prompt that we're using for the deep research tool that we have.
然后我们就在这里调用 Gemini API
And then we're just calling the Gemini API here.
并拿到回答文本和对应的来源
And we're getting the answer text and the sources.
接着在这段代码里
Then in this part of the code,
我们只是，呃，我的意思是
we're just... so, I mean,
每次你从 Gemini API 拿到来源信息时
every time you get sources from Gemini API,
它都不是结构化的
it's not in a structured form.
所以我们会在这里把它整理成更好的结构
So here we're just trying to structure it in a better way.
我运行的时候会给你看
I'll show that to you when I run it.
你会看到输出是这种结构：我们有 URL
You'll see that we get the output in this structure where we get the URL,
有标题，还有片段内容
we get the title, and we get the snippets.
而且你知道的，我们终于要把研究结果返还给大家
And, you know, finally, we are returning the research results.
所以，这就是关于我们第一个工具的全部细节
So, you know, this is all the details about our first tool.
接下来我们看第二个工具
But going on to our second tool,
也就是 YouTube 视频分析
which is the YouTube video analysis.
它的结构和我刚才展示的 deep research 工具是一样的
So this has also got the same structure as the deep research tool that I showed you.
也是三样东西，第一是工具名称
So three things. The first is the name of the tool.
第二是它使用的参数
The second is the arguments that it is using.
所以在这个例子里
So even in this case,
它同样使用工作目录和 YouTube URL
it is using the working directory and the YouTube URL.
然后是关于这个工具的详细说明
And then the details about the tool.
比如它在做什么
You know, what it is doing.
以及我们这些参数的详细说明
And the details about the arguments that we have.
最后我们只是返回这个工具的执行结果
And then we're just returning the execution of the tool.
接下来更详细地看一下 analyze YouTube video 这个工具长什么样
So going into more details about what the analyze YouTube video tool looks like.
这里就是它的实现
So here is the implementation for that.
和 deep research 工具一样
Similar to what we did for the deep research tool,
我们会在这里校验所有路径
we're validating all of the parts here.
然后我们会用这个 get video ID 函数提取 YouTube 视频 ID
And then, you know, we're taking out the YouTube video ID using this get video ID function.
如果我们没能从提供的 YouTube URL 中拿到视频 ID
If we do not get the video ID for the YouTube URL that we have provided,
我们会，呃，尝试清洗这个结果再去获取视频 ID
we get... we try to sanitize the result and get the video ID.
然后我们会调用——就在这一行——调用 Gemini API
And then, you know, we're calling... this is the line where we're calling the Gemini API.
和 deep research 工具类似
And similar to the deep research tool,
我们会返回所有这些不同的细节，这样
we're returning all of these different details so that,
我们就能跟踪所有内容
you know, we can keep track of the things.
我们可以看到自己拿到的输出是什么
We can see what is the output that we have got.
接下来我们深入看一下 analyze YouTube video 的实现
And let's go into the analyze YouTube video implementation.
和 deep research 工具类似
So, you know, similar to the deep research tool,
我们也有一个用于 YouTube 转录的提示词
we have a prompt for the YouTube transcription.
这里就是我们写好的提示词
And here is the prompt that we have written.
我们在里面就是说，你需要……这基本上是在引导 Gemini
So, you know, we're just saying that you have to... this is basically guiding the Gemini
API 按某种格式给我们返回转录内容
API to give us the transcript in a certain format.
并在输出中给出我们想要的所有说明和细节
And, you know, give us all of the instructions and the details that we want in our output.
所以在这一部分，呃
So, for this part... so,
在这里我们会
here we are, you know,
把请求分成两部分
dividing our requests into two parts.
也就是我们发给 Gemini API 的请求
The requests that we're sending the Gemini API.
第一部分我们会发送文件，呃
In the first part, we are sending the file...
不好意思，第一部分我们会把已有的那个 YouTube URL 作为 file URI 发送
sorry. In the first part, we are sending the URL that the YouTube URL that we have as a file URI.
而在第二部分
And in the second part,
我们会发送刚才给你看的那个提示词
we're sending the prompt that I showed you.
而且你知道吧，这真的是一件非常酷的事情
And, you know, this is like a very cool thing.
所以，如果你……就是，Gemini 是一个多模态模型
So, if you... so, Gemini is a multimodal model.
而且它实际上……当你把一个 YouTube 链接作为文件 URI 发给它时
And it actually... when you send a YouTube URL as a file URI,
它是真的在“看”这个视频
it actually sees the video.
它会一段一段地处理
So, it goes through part by part.
它不会去访问任何形式的字幕稿
It doesn't access any sort of transcript.
这也就是为什么当我们运行 YouTube 视频分析工具时
And that's why when we'll be running the YouTube video analyzer tool,
你会发现它需要两到三分钟
you'll see that it takes two to three minutes.
因为它真的是在处理你整段视频
Because it is actually going through your entire video.
所以它是真正的多模态
So, it is really multimodal.
我的意思是，在这里我们其实是
I mean, in here, we are,
把请求发送给 Gemini
you know, sending the request to Gemini.
然后当我们拿到输出之后
And once we get the output,
我们会尝试把拿到的输出清洗成某种特定格式
we try to clean the output that we are getting in a certain format.
接着再把它输出并保存到我们得到的 .memory 文件夹里
And then, you know, outputting it and saving it in the .memory folder that we get.
最后，再回到我们拥有的最后一个工具
Finally, coming back to the final tool that we have,
也就是汇总研究工具
which is the compiled research tool.
它在这里基本上做的事情就是返回并汇总我们拿到的所有结果
So, what it basically does here is it returns and compiles all of the results that we get
这些结果来自前面两个工具
from the previous two tools.
如果你到这里来看一下汇总研究工具的实现
If you go here and see the implementation for the compiled research tool,
你会看到它要做的事情是把内容写入输出的 research MD 文件
you will see that what it is trying to do is it is trying to write to the output research MD file.
然后它会给我们一个类似成功状态或者返回消息
And then it gives us like a success status or a return message.
所以你看，我们已经看过是如何在 MCP 服务器里注册这个工具的
So, you know, we have seen how we have registered the tool in the MCP server.
同样地，我们还有
Similarly, we've got the,
用来注册资源的代码
you know, code for registering the resources.
所以这里就是我们作为资源共享给智能体的所有内容
So, you know, here is all the things that we are sharing with the agent as resources.
比如说，我们这个服务器的名字是什么
So, basically, what is the name of the server that we have?
我们用的版本是什么
The version that we're using?
我们在用哪一种 Gemini 模型
What sort of Gemini model are we using?
我们的 YouTube 转写模型是什么
What is our YouTube transcription model?
以及所有这些不同的细节，都会通过资源的形式提供给智能体
And all of these different details are being provided to the agent using resources.
然后是 MCP 提示词
And then the MCP prompt.
所以你看，这是我们注册 MCP 提示词的方式
So, you know, this is how we have registered the MCP prompt.
基本上，我们会返回一个叫做工作流指令的东西
So, basically, we're returning something called workflow instructions.
而这就是我们写好的详细提示词
And this is the detailed prompt that we have written.
基本上，在这个提示词里
So, basically, in this prompt,
我们在告诉智能体：这些是你可以使用的工具
we are telling the agent that these are the tools that are available to you.
而且你可以用这个工作流来调用这些工具
And, you know, you can use this workflow to use these tools.
还有一些额外的细节，比如
And, you know, some additional details about,
工作目录是什么，以及所有结果应该存在哪里
like, the working directory and where all of the results should be stored.
所以你看，这是我们提供给智能体的一份详细提示词
So, you know, this is a detailed prompt that we're giving to the agent.
太好了，那回到……你知道的
Awesome. So, going back... you know,
这就像是……呃，抱歉
this is like the... sorry.
我还想在这里强调一件事，就是这是我们的 env 文件
One more thing I wanted to highlight here is that this is our N file.
所以你看，这一切都是作为资源被访问的
So, you know, this is all being accessed as resources.
但你需要在这里添加你的 Google API key
But this is where you would have to add your Google API key.
如果你想要做一些可观测性，你也可以在这里加上 Opik API key
You can add the Opik API key if you want any sort of observability.
但这就是我们使用的 .env 文件
But this is the .env file that we have.
此外，除了这些之外
Additionally, apart from that,
我们这里还有一些脚本
you know, we have the scripts here,
这些脚本就是那种
which are, like, you know,
在整个过程中帮我们处理代码的脚本
helping us with the code throughout.
而且你看，这些
And, you know, these are,
是我们额外写的脚本，用来管理一些工具函数
like, scripts we have written additionally to manage some of the utils.
所以……不好意思，嗯，回到刚才
So... sorry. Yeah. Going back.
现在我们已经有了完整的架构
So, now we have the entire architecture there.
那么，我们到底要怎么把它和我们的智能体框架连接起来呢
And so, how do we exactly connect it with our agent harness?
在我们的例子里，这个框架是 Claude Code
In our case, this is Claude Code.
所以这其实是一个非常直接的方式
So, this is a very, you know, straightforward way.
对于 Claude，你只需要在项目根目录创建一个 mcp.json 文件
For Claude, you just need to create an mcp.json file in the project root.
然后给它配置像这样的命令
And, you know, give it a command like this.
然后在我们的场景里
And then for our case,
我们是在本地运行 MCP 的
we are running the MCP locally.
也就是说，我们没有把它部署到任何地方
You know, we're not hosting it anywhere.
它就是在本地运行
It's being run locally.
而且它使用标准输入
And it's using standard in,
标准输出来进行通信
standard out for communication.
所以你看，这样是可行的
So, you know, this works.
但是以防万一，你也知道，你的 MCP 是托管在别的地方
But in case, you know, your MCP is hosted elsewhere,
那你就需要一个 url
you would need an url.
Notion 就是一个非常常见的例子
Notion is a very popular example.
Notion 有它自己托管的 MCP
Notion has its own hosted MCP.
你可以通过拿到那个 url 来访问它
You can have access to it by getting the url.
所以这部分代码就需要做一点修改
So, this part of the code would be changed slightly.
不再是写 uv 命令
Instead of putting the uv command,
你就会，你知道，而不是输入那个 uv 命令
you would be, you know, instead of putting the uv command,
而是在这里填上那个 url
you would have that url here.
这样你就可以连接到
And you can connect with,
任何可用的 MCP
you know, any MCP that is available.
比如 Snowflake、Notion，或者你想用的任何东西
Snowflake, Notion, anything that you want.
我还想在这里再强调一件事
One more thing that I would like to highlight here is that,
就像我在演讲一开始说的那样
as I said at the beginning of my talk,
我们用的是 Claude Code 作为智能体框架
we're using Claude Code as an agent harness.
你可以用任何你想用的东西
You can use anything that you want.
比如说，如果你喜欢 Copilot
You know, if you like Copilot,
你也可以用它来做这件事
you can use it for this.
任何你想用的智能体框架
You know, any sort of agent harness you want to use,
都可以拿来做这件事
you can use it for that.
但这里讲的是 Claude Code 的用法
But this is for Claude Code.
好，那我们来看一下那个文件在哪
Okay. So, let's see where that file is.
所以它在……所以你必须在根目录下创建那个 mcp.json 文件
So, it's in the... so, you have to create that mcp.json file in the root directory.
然后这个文件……我可以给你讲一下
And this is... I can explain it to you.
它其实非常简单
It's a very simple thing.
所以在这里我们有
So, here we have, you know,
我们这个 MCP 服务器的名字
the name of the MCP server we have.
也就是 deep research
So, you know, it's deep research.
然后这是我们配置的命令
And this is the command that we have.
所以我们使用 uv 是因为它把一切都简化了
So, we're using uv because it simplifies everything.
所以你知道，无论你创建的是哪种虚拟环境
So, you know, any sort of virtual environment that you're creating,
无论你在下载什么东西、什么包
any sort of things, packages that you're downloading,
全部都由 uv 来处理
it's all being handled by uv,
所以你自己基本不用做什么
so you don't have to do anything.
然后我们还有这个命令
And then we have this command,
它基本上就是在运行我几分钟前给你们看的那个服务器文件
which is basically running the server file that I showed you a couple of minutes ago.
所以它就只是做这件事
So, it is just doing that.
所以 Claude 会在本地把这个服务器文件作为子进程来运行
So, Claude runs the server file as a subprocess locally.
所以我们的服务器是跑在本地的
So, our server is running locally.
然后这整段代码就是…不好意思
And this entire code is... sorry,
整个命令就只是在做这件事
this entire command is only doing that.
它的意思是运行 fast mcp
It says run fast mcp,
运行并指定我们已有的服务器文件路径
run and path to the server file that we have.
这是我之前说过你需要自己创建的环境文件
And this is the environment file that I told you that you're supposed to create.
好的，那么现在是时候来看一下这段代码是怎么工作的了
Okay. So, you know, now it's time to see how the code works.
所以我会切到 Claude 里
So, I would go to Claude.
抱歉
Sorry.
好，如果你打开 Claude 然后选择 mcp
Okay. So, if you go to Claude and you do mcp,
你可以看到我这里有两个服务器
you can see that I have two servers here.
因为我有那个 mcp 的 JSON 文件
So, because of the mcp JSON file that I have,
它就能自动检测到这两个智能体
it was automatically able to detect both the agents.
所以我们现在只看这个深度研究智能体
So, we'll just be seeing the deep research agent right now.
这里是所有的详细信息
And this is all the details.
你可以看到命令
You can see the command.
你可以看到我们有哪些参数
You can see the arguments that we have.
你可以看到服务器对外暴露的所有能力
You can see all of the capabilities that the server is exposing.
你可以直接点“view tools”来看
So, you can just do view tools.
你就能看到这些工具的所有详细信息
And you can see all of the details about the tools.
比如工具名、我之前给你们看的描述
So, the tool name, the description that I showed you,
还有所有的参数
all of the arguments,
以及我们定义的各个参数
the parameters that we have.
其他所有工具也是类似的
You know, similarly for all of the other tools,
你都可以在这里看到全部细节
you can see all of the details here.
现在我打算试着…
Now, you know, I'm gonna try to...
抱歉
sorry.
我打算试着
I'm gonna try to, you know,
运行其中一个工具，看一下 Claude 是怎么用它的
run one of the tools and see how Claude does it.
我已经事先写好了这个问题
So, I've already written out this question.
这是之前一场关于 AI 智能体的分享里的问题
This was from a previous AI talk about AI agents.
所以我就让它帮我分析这个视频
So, I'm gonna just tell it to analyze this video for me.
它应该可以自动检测到我们在外部暴露出来的那个工具
And it should automatically be able to detect the tool that we have that is being exposed
也就是由 MCP 服务器提供的工具
by the MCP server.
你可以看到
So, you can see here that,
它已经自动选中了我们暴露出来的那个工具
you know, it is automatically picked up the tool that we are exposing.
并且正在尝试使用它
And it is trying to use that.
同时在旁边
And on the side, you know,
你可以看到有一个 .memory 文件夹，就是我之前提到的那个
you can see that there's a .memory folder that I told you,
我们会在里面记录所有结果
you know, where we are tracking all of our results.
它已经被创建出来了，并且会把转录写入这个文件
It is being created and it's gonna write the transcript to this file.
正如我说过的，Gemini 正在观看
So, as I told you, Gemini is watching or,
或者说在实时分析这个视频
like, analyzing this video in real time.
这就是为什么它会花
That's why it's taking... it's gonna take,
大概几分钟时间
like, a couple of minutes for it to,
来生成这份转录
like, produce the transcript.
嗯，就是这样
So, yeah.
基本上，每次你给出这样的问题时
So, basically, every time you get this question,
Claude Code 会先判断自己能做些什么
you know, Claude Code tries to see what it can do,
看有哪些可用的工具
what tools are being available.
然后它会向 MCP 服务器发送请求，请求执行这个工具
And, you know, then it sends a request to the MCP server that can you please execute this tool.
当 MCP 把这个工具执行完之后
And once the MCP executes the tool,
它会把结果发回 Claude Code，Claude 再对这个结果做进一步分析
it sends the results back to Claude Code and then it further analyzes that result.
所以我们可以稍微等一会儿
So, we can wait a minute for that.
抱歉，好，现在它已经创建好了这个 markdown 文件
Sorry. Yeah. So, it has created this markdown file.
它说这个视频来自
So, it says that this video is from,
AI 工程师代码峰会
you know, the AI engineer code summit.
它给了我所有的详细信息
It has provided me all of the details.
而且你可以看到，这是一份
And, you know, it is,
质量相当不错、细节很完整的转录
like, pretty good detailed transcript that we can see here.
而且它还会在最后
And, you know, it also gives,
给出它自己的看法
you know, gives its input at the end.
另外我也特别喜欢的一点是
Plus, I also, like, really like this thing that,
我们既把完整转录都存了下来
you know, we are storing all of the transcript.
但同时它还会给你
But it gives you, like,
在底部附上一段非常简洁的总结
a really neat summary at the bottom where it says,
告诉你这个视频里分享的关键观点是什么
you know, what were the key ideas that were shared in the video.
然后它还会说明
And, you know, so... and it says that,
好的，完整转录在这里
okay, the transcript is here.
所以你可以看到，这是一个
So, you know, this is,
简短的示例，展示我们如何
like, a short example of how we could,
运行并检查某个工具，看它能不能顺利跑起来
you know, run and see one of the tools if it's able to run that or not.
接下来我会尝试
And now I will try to,
再次运行整条流水线
you know, run the entire pipeline again.
好
Okay.
我已经为此写好了一条问题
So, I've already written a question for that.
我在让它做一次端到端的研究
So, I'm telling it to do an end-to-end research.
然后
And so,
现在我打算同时使用我这边的深度研究工具和 YouTube 视频工具
now I'm trying to use the deep research tool that I have and the YouTube video tool that I have.
想要看一下
And trying to see, you know,
它是如何把这两个工具一起跑起来的
how it runs both of them together.
它说自己会先执行“分析 YouTube 视频”这一步
So, it says that it is trying to do the analyze YouTube video part first.
所以当你有
So, when you have, like,
像这样比较大的问题时
a, you know, like, a big question like this,
整个工作流的运行方式是 Claude 会把问题拆解成
the entire workflow, how it works is Claude breaks down the question into,
不同的部分，然后判断各部分需要用到哪些工具
like, different parts and then sees which tool it needs.
所以你知道，它在里面就像有一整套推理在运转，然后
So, you know, it has, like, an entire reasoning going on that,
好，如果我现在手头有这些工具
okay, you know, if these are the sort of tools that I have available,
那我需要用 YouTube…分析 YouTube 视频这个工具来分析视频
I need the YouTube... analyze YouTube video tool for analyzing the YouTube video.
我需要用深度搜索工具…深度研究工具来处理问题的第一部分
I need the deep search tool... deep research tool for the first part of the question.
所以它会把这个分成两部分然后尝试去调用
So, it's gonna divide it into two parts and then try to call,
就是两个工具都调用
like, both the tools.
好的 我们来看一下
Okay. Let's see.
嗯
Yeah.
不好意思 它通常需要一点时间才能
Sorry. It usually takes some time for it to...
好的
Sure.
嗯
Yeah.
我接下来其实要讲的 正好就是下一部分
I'm actually gonna talk... that's the next part.
一开始我在把它移到临时文件夹的时候是想把这个skill去掉 这样
I was trying to remove the skill initially when I moved it to the temporary folder so that
它就不会再加载这个skill
it doesn't pick up the skill,
因为它也很容易这么做
because it tends to do that as well.
不是说这个 只是关于prompt那一部分
Not about that. Just the prompt part, though.
不是的 对我们来说
Not... so, I mean, for us,
我们是用skill来替换掉prompt那一部分
we're using the skill and replacing the prompt part.
也就是说我们在尝试用整套东西
So, you know, trying to use that entire thing.
我一会儿会给你们演示
I'll show it to you, like,
就一分钟之后
just in a minute.
我觉得那样可能就能回答你们的问题
I think that might clarify your question.
所以在这里它给了我 你看
So, I mean, here it gives me... you know,
它又是在分析这个 YouTube 视频
it is, like, analyze the YouTube video again.
它在第一部分没有把完整答案都给出来
It didn't give me the entire answer for the first part.
不过 我觉得它只是 你们先给我一秒
But, yeah, I mean, I think it just... just give me one second.
我得把当前对话的上下文清掉
I have to clear the context of the plot,
因为它总是会用到我之前问过的东西
because it tends to use whatever I asked it previously.
而且我还得
And I also had to, like,
把memory文件夹删掉
delete the memory folder.
所以在这段时间里 你们知道
So, till the time, you know,
这个东西正在运行并且帮我们生成研究内容
this is, you know, running and generating research for us.
不好意思 在它
Sorry. Till the time it's, like,
运行并生成研究内容的这段时间里
running and generating research,
我可以先讲一下我们接下来的那一页
I could talk about the next slide that we have.
就是agent skill
Which is the agent skill.
所以我相信你们所有人肯定都已经听说过很多关于那个所谓的代理技能
So, I'm sure all of you must have heard a lot about, you know, agent skill.
现在非常流行
It is very popular right now.
所以这基本上是一个很紧凑
So, this is basically a compact,
很精炼的方式来
concise way of, you know,
告诉智能体有哪些能力和workflow
telling agent about capabilities and workflows.
然后 基本上
And, you know, so, basically,
工具负责干活
tools do the work.
而skill则提供你怎么去做的方式
And, you know, skills provide you the way to do it.
我们之前讲过我给你们看的那整段prompt
So, you know, we talked about the entire prompt that I showed you.
就是我们那个workflow prompt
You know, the workflow prompt that we have.
在那里面 我们是在告诉 不好意思
In that, you know, we were telling... sorry.
我们是在告诉我们的智能体
We were telling our agent that,
好 这些是可用的工具
okay, you know, these are the tools that are available.
以及你应该如何调用它们
And this is how you should execute them.
但不是那种，你懂的，直接把它写在提示里
But instead of, you know, writing it in the prompt,
我们可以把它做成一个skill
we can instead create a skill out of that.
那这样做有什么好处呢
And what is the benefit of doing that?
当一个东西已经能解决问题的时候
You know, when one thing is already solving the problem,
为什么还要再做一个
why should we create another one?
原因是skill有一个叫渐进式暴露的特性
The reason for that is that skill has something called progressive disclosure.
所以当你，你知道的，就像我当时那样，你知道
So, when you, you know, like I did, you know,
当我给你们演示的时候 我一会儿会再给你们看
when I showed you... I'm gonna show it to you in a minute.
当你加载这个skill的时候
When you load the skill.
所以你知道吧 当Claude就那样把这个技能展示给你看时
So, you know, when Claude just, like, shows you the skill,
它并不会把所有信息都加载进来
it doesn't load the entire information.
它只会加载skill的名字和描述
It is only load the name and the description of the skill.
当你真正跑一个query的时候
Once you run a query,
它才会把完整内容都加载进来
it's gonna load the entire thing.
而当这个query执行完之后
And once that query is executed,
它会把这些内容全部清掉
it is gonna wipe off everything.
所以这些东西就不会一直留在上下文里
So, you know, it is not gonna be there in the context.
但如果你用的是prompt
Whereas when you're using prompt,
所有东西都会一直待在上下文里
you know, everything is gonna be there in the context.
它会非常相信上下文里的内容
It's gonna believe the context.
所以你通常会想要避免这种情况
And so, you know, you'd want to avoid that.
因此skill是一个非常干净的方式来
So, you know, skills are a very clean way of,
实现这一点
you know, doing that.
而且它也非常容易分享
And it is also very shareable.
因为我们在内部会为团队写很多skill 然后彼此共享
Because, you know, we internally write a lot of skills for our team and share it with each other.
所以这是一种非常
So, it's a very, you know,
简洁又易于分享的方式
it's a concise, shareable way.
而且更容易维护
And it's more maintainable.
因为你可以把它提交到GitHub
Because, you know, you can check it into GitHub.
那就像你的首选位置 你可以在那儿把整套东西都搞定
It's like your go-to place and you can do the entire thing there.
所以
So...
好 现在我们已经有这个的结果了
okay. So, we have the results for this.
但在看结果之前 我想先给你们看一下我们是怎么写这些skill的
But before that, I would just like to show you how we have written the skills.
好的 所以 我们已经把research相关的skill写好了
Okay. So... I mean, we've written the research skills.
这个就是用来替换我们原来的prompt
So, this is replacing the prompt that we have.
在这里你需要写上你想要的skill名称
So, here we have to write the name of the skill that you want.
你还需要写上描述
You need to write the description.
那为什么这个描述是必要的呢
So, why this description is necessary?
因为当你的智能体在尝试
Because when your agent is trying to,
把一个query匹配到某个skill上的时候
you know, match a query to a skill,
它会看这一部分
it is gonna look at this part of,
就是skill里的这一块内容
you know, this part of the skill.
所以你需要在这里写一个比较好的描述
So, you need to have like a good description here.
然后这一块就叫front matter 会被加载进来
And, you know, then this is called the front matter, which is loaded.
接下来就是skill剩下的主体部分
And then this is like the rest of the part of the skill.
在我们的例子里
So, in our case, you know,
我们是复用之前的research workflow prompt 而不是把所有细节都写在这里
we are reusing the research workflow prompt that we had instead of writing all of the details in here.
你当然也可以那样做 但对我们来说这是一个设计选择
You can do that, but it's a design choice for us.
然后这里就是这个skill剩下的主体内容
And, you know, this is like the rest of the body for the skill.
好 那现在你要怎么查看所有这些skill呢
Okay. So, now, how could you see all of those skills?
我说它只加载前置信息是什么意思
And what do I mean that it only loads the front matter?
所以如果你再打开Claude
So, if you go to Claude again,
然后如果你做…不好意思
and if you do... sorry.
如果你点进skills，你就能看到
If you do skills, you'll be able to see.
这些就是我已经下载好的一些技能
So, these are some of the skills that I've already downloaded.
这些是我们创建的项目技能
And these are the project skills that we have created.
尤其是我刚才提到的那个research技能
So, particularly the research skill that I was talking about.
所以每次你这样操作并看到这个的时候
And so, every time you do this and you see this,
只会加载前置信息
only the front matter is loaded,
而不是整个描述内容
not the entire description.
对吧 然后你其实可以…如果你想用这个的话
Right? And you can actually... if you want to use this,
你只要像这样操作就行
you can just do something like this.
或者当你问它问题时 Claude可以自动调用这个技能
Or Claude can automatically pick up the skill when you ask it a question.
现在我打算问它之前我想通过MCP问的那个同样的问题…好
Now, I'm gonna try to ask it the same question I was trying to ask the MCP with... okay.
所以我要让它先研究一下AI智能体有哪些技能 然后再
So, I'm gonna ask it that it researches what an AI agent's skills are and then also
帮我分析这个YouTube视频
analyzes the YouTube video for me.
嗯 它正在加载research工作流的提示词
Yeah. So, it is loading the research workflow prompt.
它之所以能这么做 是因为我们的服务器在本地运行
And it is able to do that because our server is running locally.
这也是它能读取这个prompt的原因
And that's why it's able to read the prompt.
因为它们都在同一个文件夹里
Because they're all in the same folder.
现在它已经开始做深度研究
And now it has started to do a deep research,
你在这里可以看到
you can see here.
不好意思
Sorry.
所以它已经创建了…所以
So, it has created... so,
它现在正在运行 你知道的
it is running, you know,
在这里跑深度研究
the deep research here.
然后它已经运行了 比如说 首先
And then it has run, like... firstly,
它先运行了分析YouTube视频的工具
it ran the analyze YouTube video tool.
接着它在运行深度研究工具
Then it is running the deep research tool.
我觉得这里有一点特别棒 我想强调一下 就是最初的
And I think one amazing thing here that I would like to highlight is that the initial
我的查询是
query that I had was,
就是 你能给我详细讲讲什么是智能体技能吗
you know, can you give me details about what are agent skills?
然后每一次 你知道
And every time, you know,
我们的智能体框架都会识别它拿到的输出里存在的空白
our agent harness identifies the gap in the output that it gets.
所以在我最初的问题里
So, in my initial question,
它会识别出里面所有存在的空白
it is gonna identify all of the gaps that exist.
然后它会每次再问一个不同的问题来填补这些空白
And then it's gonna ask a different question every time to fill that gap.
所以你看 它在幕后做所有推理 并确保
So, you know, it is doing all of the reasoning behind the scene and making sure,
在我们要做的这项研究里 把这些空白都补上
you know, all of those gaps are filled in the research that we're trying to do.
嗯 一般来说 跑完整个输出大概需要两到三分钟
So, yeah. I mean, it usually takes around two to three minutes for me to run this entire output.
我们等等看
Let's see.
好的
Sure.
嗯 我是说 我们一开始是基于
Yeah. So, I mean, we built it originally with,
你知道的 它的MCP那一部分来构建的
you know, the MCP portion of it.
现在我们正在做迁移
And now, you know, we are transitioning.
但我们想保留原来的代码
But we want to keep our original code.
呃 我是说 不是服务器那一部分
And... I mean, not the server part.
而是核心的prompt部分
But the prompt, essentially,
我们现在有的这些 可以用skills来替换
that we have, we can replace it with skills.
是 但我的意思是 我们在服务器里有很多细节和不同组件
Yeah, but I mean, we have a lot of detailing and different components within the servers.
这就是我们想保留那部分的原因
That's the reason we wanted to maintain that.
嗯
Yeah.
在这种情况下更多是因为复杂度
It's more of the complexity in that case.
所以我们才想把它保留下来
That's why we want to maintain that.
所以在这里你可以看到
So, here we can see, you know,
我们已经拿到了视频的输出
we've got the output of the video.
现在我们只需要等它生成MCP文件的输出
And now we're just gonna wait for it to produce the output for the MCP file.
太好了 你看 这里我们已经拿到了…这是我一开始问它的问题
Perfect. So, you know, here you can see we've got... this was my initial question that I asked it.
然后它已经给了我这个问题的答案
And, you know, it has given me the answer for that.
这是我们做的第一次运行
And this is, like, the first run that we have had.
现在它就 相当于
And now it's, like, you know,
在这个基础上做更多研究
doing, like, more research on that.
因为它 你知道
Because it, you know,
它已经给了我们一个答案
gave us an answer.
但它识别出了里面还存在一些空白
But it identifies some of the gaps in that.
所以这是它跑的第二个查询
So, this is the second query it ran.
这是一个不一样的问题
And this is, like, a different question.
你可以在这里看到
You can see here.
对吧 所以它跑了两个查询
Right? So, it ran two queries.
然后它觉得 好
And it was, like, okay,
这个已经足够好了
you know, this is good enough.
然后它说 三个研究任务都已经完成
And then it says all three research tasks are completed.
让我再跑一个更有针对性的查询 然后把所有内容收尾
Let me run one more targeted query and then complete everything.
所以你看 这就是为什么我们希望
So, you know, that's why we wanted,
把所有推理都交给智能体来做
you know, all of the reasoning to be done by agents.
因为你知道 这就是人类会做的事情
Because, you know, this is something a human would do.
因为如果你在读一篇文章
Because if you're reading an article,
或者在做任何形式的研究
or if you're doing any sort of research,
你都会试着找出里面的空白 然后把它补上
you try to identify the gaps and try to fill it with that.
所以你看 这正是它在尝试做的事
So, you know, that's what it is trying to do.
这也是为什么我们需要这么多“脑力”
And that's why we needed all of the brain.
并且在努力把它利用起来
And, you know, are trying to utilize that.
所以你看 这是
So, you know, this is,
它帮我跑的第三个查询
like, the third query that it is running for me.
然后最后 我们预期它会
And then finally, we expected to,
生成一份整理好的综合报告
like, create, like, a compiled report.
很快就会出来
Which is going to be any minute.
好
Sure.
我觉得…我是说 那个
I think... I mean, that is,
就是…我们得
like... I mean, we would have to,
去看一下那一块的可观测性数据
like, see the observability for that.
然后检查并找出为什么它没有
And, like, check and identify why it is not,
识别到最新的代码
like, seeing the latest code.
但我们也给了它一个来自2025年的视频
But we also have given it a video from 2025.
所以我觉得可能是因为这个原因
So, I think maybe it's because of that.
所以我让它处理的那个视频
So, the video that I asked it to,
就是让它转写的那个 是跟这个相关的
like, transcribe, it is regarding that.
但我觉得要更好地回答这个问题
But I think to probably answer that better,
我需要深入到我们代码里所有可观测性相关的部分
I would, like, go into all of the observability part of the code that we have.
然后看看那里到底发生了什么
And, like, see what is going on there.
所以你知道，最后呢
So, you know, finally,
它在问我能不能帮我创建一个 markdown 文件
it's asking me if it could create a markdown file for me.
所以，这就是我们最终工具生成的研究 MD 文件
And so, here is the research MD file that our final tool creates.
而且你知道，它真的非常详细
And, you know, it is really detailed.
它包含了所有的对比表格
It has got all of the comparison tables.
而且它还包含了那种
And it has got, like,
各种细节内容
all of the details.
所以我觉得这是一个把目前为止所有成果汇总起来的非常好的方式
So, you know, I think this is a really nice way to compile everything that we have gotten so far.
它还会整理并附上我们已有的 YouTube 视频链接
And it also, like, compiles and adds the YouTube video link that we have.
抱歉，是把我们的视频字幕稿放在底部
Sorry, video transcript that we have at the bottom.
好的，非常感谢大家
So, yeah. Thank you so much, everyone.
现在我把时间交给保罗
Now I'll hand it over to Paul.
太棒了
Awesome.
谢谢路易-弗朗索瓦和萨姆里迪
Thank you, Luis and Samriddhi,
感谢你们做的精彩幻灯片
for those great slides.
请给我一点时间在这边把一切都设置好
And just give me a second to set up everything over here.
好的，现在我们要进入整个系统的第三部分
Okay. So, now we are moving to part three of this whole system,
也就是领英写作工作流
which is the LinkedIn writing workflow,
它基本上是把深度研究智能体产出的研究内容转化成精修过的帖子，这些帖子
which basically transforms this research from deep research agents to Polish posts that
能通过烂文检测器，这样我们就能把你们都变成领英影响力人物
pass slot detectors, so we can transform all of you into LinkedIn influencers.
好的，先做一个高层概览
Okay. So, just like a high-level overview,
这是我们完整的系统架构
this is our full system architecture, right?
我们已经实现了研究智能体
So, we did... we already implemented the research agent,
它会输出这个研究 MD 文件
which outputs this research MD file,
这个文件会作为写作工作流的输入
which will be as input to the writing workflow,
在此基础之上
which, on top of that,
还会额外输入 guideline.md 文件
has as input the guideline.md file,
它本质上就是一种更讲究的方式来表达用户输入
which basically is a fancy way to put... it's a fancy way of the user input,
我们会用这种方式来建模用户输入，从而引导生成过程
and this is how we will model the user input to guide the generation process.
而最终的输出会是
And the final output will be,
也就是领英帖子
well, the LinkedIn posts, right?
好的，现在我们来真正放大看看这个架构
Okay. Now, let's actually zoom in into the architecture,
它被拆分成三个大的部分
which is split into three big pieces.
第一部分是我们构建上下文的地方
So, the first one is where we build up the context,
最终我们会得到一个很大的系统提示词
and ultimately we end up with the big system prompt.
因为要记住，从根本上说
Because remember, this is... ultimately,
这不是一个智能体
this is not an agent.
它只是一个工作流
This is just a workflow,
因为在现实中
because in reality, like,
要写一篇内容
to write a piece of content,
不管是什么
regardless of what it is,
是领英帖子、视频
a LinkedIn post, a video,
还是文章，其实你并不真的需要智能体
or an article, you don't really need agents, right?
因为就像路易-弗朗索瓦一开始说的
Because, as Luis said in the beginning,
这个流程其实是非常静态的
this process can be... it's very static.
你基本上总是在走同样的步骤
You always kind of go through always the same steps,
所以引入智能体只会让一切变得复杂得多
so an agent will just make everything a lot complicated.
当然，你可以在其中某些部分加入智能体
Of course, you can put agents in some parts of it,
但我们在这个工作坊里不会展示这一点
but we won't show that into this workshop.
所以第一步是加载上下文
So, the first part is to load the context,
也就是我刚才说的 guideline 和那个文件
which is, as I said, the guideline and the file,
它们是用户输入
which is the user input,
还有研究内容，然后我们还有一些静态文件
the research, and then we have some static files,
包括人物画像和少样本示例
the profiles, and a few-shot examples,
这些我稍后会更详细地讲
which I will dig into more detail a bit later.
所以我们把这些全部拿过来
So, we take all of this,
构建系统提示词
build the system prompt,
然后把所有内容传给语言模型
and then pass everything to the LLM.
这就是第二阶段
So, this is phase two.
到目前为止没什么花哨的
So, so far, nothing fancy.
我们基本上就是创建一个巨大的系统提示词，然后调用语言模型来生成第一版
We just basically create this huge system prompt and call the LLM to create the first
帖子的草稿
draft of the post.
然后最后一个阶段是应用评估器-优化器循环
And then, the last phase is to apply the evaluator optimizer loop,
这可能是整个流程里最有趣的部分
which is probably the most interesting part of this,
在这里我们让语言模型循环生成评审意见，并对帖子进行几轮修改
where we let the LLM to create in a loop reviews and edit the post a couple of times, right?
这点非常重要，因为
So, this is super important because,
实际上你不仅可以把它用在领英帖子上
in reality, you can apply this not only to LinkedIn posts,
还可以用在几乎任何类型的内容上
but to, like, any type of content,
比如从视频字幕稿到各类报告
like, starting from video transcripts to reports,
财报、医疗报告
financial reports, medical reports,
甚至是文章，或者说
even articles or, like,
书的章节，或者非常详细的文章式课程
book chapters or very detailed article lessons,
就像我们在课程里做的那样
as we did in our course,
在那里我们需要遵循
where we needed to follow,
各种文本片段、图片、代码片段、参考文献
like, text snippets, images, code snippets, references,
以及所有这些细枝末节，而语言模型有时能处理对
and all these little details that the LLMs usually sometimes get right,
但更多时候处理得并不对
but most often don't get right.
即便它在 80% 的情况下是对的
And even if they get right 80% of the time,
你还是得手动去修那些错误，这就很烦人
it's annoying to manually go and fix that, right?
这就是关键所在
That's the whole point.
所以这一切都是端到端自动化完成的
So, all of this is automated end-to-end.
我们稍后会再更深入地讲解这个流程
So, we'll dig again into this process in more depth later on.
这是我们的一个示例
So, this is just one of our examples.
这是我们让系统生成的一篇领英帖子的开头部分
So, this is the beginning of a LinkedIn post that we asked to generate.
只是为了好玩，我想把这篇帖子复制一下
And just for fun, I just want to copy this post.
把完全相同的帖子粘贴到这个
So, it's the exact same post and put it into this,
还挺流行的烂文评分检测器里
like, pretty popular slop score detector.
这样你们就可以相信这套东西确实有效
So, you can trust me that this actually works.
然后点分析，结果是，太好了，不是烂文
And hit analyze. And yay, not slop.
而且它的烂文评分实际上比人类写的还要低
And this is actually lower and less sloppy than a human.
你可以看到，它在下面那个位置
As you can see, it's over there on the bottom.
当然，不是所有帖子都能做到这么不“烂”
Of course, not all the posts are this not sloppish,
但大多数帖子都非常不错，而且听起来很像人写的
but most of them are really good and they sound human.
但要记住，这是领英的语言风格
But remember, this is LinkedIn language,
所以我们需要听起来多少有点“领英味儿”
so we need to sound a bit like LinkedIn, right?
但最终你可以看到
But ultimately, as you can see,
它没有任何破折号
it doesn't have any em dashes,
也没有那些奇怪的副词、动词
any weird adverbs, verbs,
以及类似的东西
and things like this.
读起来会非常顺畅
It can be read very, very nicely.
这个结构是可以模式化/可套用的
The structure is schemable,
就像我们在领英之类的平台上所希望的那样
as we would like for LinkedIn and things like that.
你可以通过这个链接在GitHub代码仓库里查看完整帖子并亲自尝试这个烂文
You can check the full post at this link in the GitHub repository and also try the slop
测试如果你没有使用那个链接的话
test yourself if you aren't using that link.
好的 那现在我们来更深入地探讨这个工作流的第一阶段
Okay. So, now let's start to dig deeper into the first phase of this workflow,
在这一阶段我们的核心关注点是弄清楚我们究竟如何才能真正控制生成过程对吧
where our core focus is understanding how we can actually control the generation, right?
因为就像路易-弗朗索瓦一开始说的那样
Because as Louis said in the beginning,
我们不想只是写一句
we don't want just to write,
嘿 我想要一篇关于主题X的领英帖子
hey, I want a LinkedIn post on topic X.
我们真正想要的是把自己的想法
We actually want to dump our ideas,
价值观和思考倾注到那篇帖子里 让它真正听起来像我们自己
values, and thoughts into that post that actually sounds like us.
所以第一个技巧其实是把这个指导说明结构化
So, the first trick is actually to structure this guideline,
也就是用户输入
which is the user input,
把它结构化得不只是“给我写一篇关于X的帖子”对吧
and structure it more than just write me a post on X, right?
这样它才能真正引导我们要写什么
So, this actually guides what we want to write.
通常我们会这样做
So, usually what we did,
我们为此创建了一个模板 需要在里面填写比如我们想要
we created a template for this where we need to fill in such as what topic we want to
讨论什么主题 想从什么角度切入
address, what angle we want to address,
想要覆盖的一些关键点
some key points we want to address,
叙事流程之类的内容
the narrative flow, and things like this.
而这部分是每篇帖子之间唯一会变化的内容
And this is the only piece that changes from post to post.
所以基本上在整个系统里
So, basically, from the whole system,
这是我们作为人类需要亲自编写的输入 用来生成不同的帖子
this is what we need to write ourselves as a human as input to write different posts.
然后就像我说的那样
And, yeah, as I said,
这一部分是动态的 会不断变化
this is dynamic and changes.
接下来 你可以在代码仓库里的这个示例以及许多
Next, and again, you can see an example here into this example from the repo along many
其他示例中看到一个例子 不过我稍后会展示
others, but I will show them a bit later.
第二个技巧是加入这些写作画像
So, the second trick is to add these writing profiles,
它们本质上是告诉语言模型这篇帖子应该怎么写 对吧
which basically tell the LLM how to write this post, right?
因为实际上你并不希望语言模型自己随便发挥
Because in reality, you don't really want the LLM to just do its own thing.
你是想对它进行引导的
You want to guide it.
而这些内容是静态的 因为
And these are static because,
就像我说的 有了指导说明
as I said, with the guideline,
你定义的是你想写什么
you define what you want to write,
而这里则是定义你想怎么写
and this is how you define how you want to write it.
它本质上是叠加在上面的风格层
It's basically the styling layer on top of it.
我们主要创建了三个画像
And we mainly created three profiles,
它们本身都是Markdown文件
which by themselves are markdown files,
分别是结构画像
which are the structure profile,
在这里我们会定义一些内容 比如一篇领英帖子平均大概有多少字符
where basically we define things such as how many characters on average a LinkedIn post
以及一篇领英帖子的核心结构
has, like the core structure of a LinkedIn post.
我们需要有开头的钩子 正文
We want the hook, like the body,
以及行动号召
the call to action.
此外 在术语层面
Also, for the terminology,
我们会定义要使用主动语态 以及要禁止使用的AI烂文/AI糟粕内容中的烂词和表达
we define things such as the active voice and the AI slop words and expressions that we want to ban.
而且不幸的是 你能做的大概也就这些
And unfortunately, this is all you can do.
你只能维护一长串Delve
You just need to keep track of a huge list of Delve,
tapestry Vibrant 以及所有那些我们“喜闻乐见”的词
tapestry, Vibrant, and all those words that we love,
然后郑重其事地要求模型不要用这些词 直到你自己作为人类也开始用它们为止
and just kindly ask them to not use them until you start using them as a human as well.
最后一个是人物画像
And the last one is the character profile,
它算是比较静态的
which is kind of static,
但你也可以对它进行配置
but you can also configure it.
比如在我们的写作工作流中
For example, in our writing workflow,
我们实际上是基于我 保罗 的个人简介来配置它的 对吧
we actually configure it under my Paul's biography, right?
这样它就会对我有一些了解
So it knows a bit about me,
比如我在写作时是怎么展开的
like how I run to write,
我喜欢怎样写 我的风格
how I like to write, my style,
以及类似的这些信息
and things like this.
这就是你如何给它注入一点个性
So this is how you can add a bit of personality to it.
所以我们会再次把所有这些内容放进系统提示词里
So again, we put all of this into the system prompt,
再加上之前定义的指导说明
plus the guideline that we defined before.
你会发现这些内容都是静态的
And you can see these are static.
所以就像我说的 我们只需要定义一次
So as I said, we define them just once,
然后你就可以在写作画像目录下访问并随便查看
and you can access them under writing profiles and look around.
那些是包含几百行文字的Markdown文件 对吧
There are, I know, Markdown files of a few hundreds of lines of words, right?
所以最后一个技巧其实是加入少样本示例
So the last trick is actually to add few-shot examples.
这本身没什么花哨的
So this is nothing fancy,
但在现实中 真正难的是把这些示例收集出来 对吧
but in reality, the hard part is actually to get them, right?
基本上这属于你系统中的数据收集部分
Basically, this is under the data collection part of your system.
在我们的这个具体用例里
And in our particular use case,
我们加入了三篇左右我自己写的领英帖子
we added kind of three LinkedIn posts from my writing.
核心思路是使用高质量且具有代表性的少样本示例 并尽量让它们
And the key idea is to use high-quality and representative few-shot examples and make them
在主题方面尽可能多样化
as varied as possible in things such as topic,
在长度 结构等方面也尽量多样化
length, structure, and so on and so forth.
有一个问题我想很多人都很好奇
And one question I think many people are curious about is,
为什么是三篇领英帖子
why three LinkedIn posts?
我知道三是个“魔法数字”
I know three is a magic number,
但实际上我只是凭感觉猜的
but in reality, I just guessed it.
关键在于 对于少样本示例来说
And the thing is that with few-shot examples,
因为你总是要在系统提示词里传入它们
because you always pass them in your system prompt,
所以你希望在能完成任务的前提下 示例数量越少越好
you want the lower number possible that gets the job done.
所以通常大家会说三
So usually people tell like three,
五 十 二十个少样本示例
five, ten, twenty few-shot examples,
但一般来说 你会先从一个较大的数量开始 然后尽可能往下删减
but usually you want to start with the bigger number and trim down that as much as
一直删到它还能正常工作为止
possible until it works.
当它不再好用时
And when it stops working,
你就再把示例加回来
you put that back in.
因为你想要保持
Because you want to keep,
也就是说 你希望带有少样本示例的系统提示词尽可能小
the idea is that you want to keep your system prompt with the few-shot examples as small
尽可能精简 因为
as possible because, well,
你每次都要把它传给语言模型
you always pass that to LLM,
这会转化为更高的成本
which translates to more cost,
更高的延迟 甚至因为内容变多而导致性能下降
more latency, and even degrading performance because the content grows.
针对这一点 我在GitHub代码仓库里提供了一个数据集 里面是我从自己的主页中抽取的
Okay, so for that, I made available a dataset in the GitHub repository where I extracted
大约20篇随机的领英帖子 它们的表现更好
like 20 random LinkedIn posts from my profile that are more,
获得了更多关注和互动
that got more traction.
所以我把它作为这个写作工作流的数据集 并在后续用来配置其他内容
So I used that as a dataset for this writing workflow and further down the line to configure other things.
需要强调的一点是 可能唯一能减少系统提示词中少样本示例负担的办法
And one thing to highlight is that probably the only way to reduce this load on the system
就是通过微调
prompt with few-shot examples is through fine-tuning,
但那往往有点小题大做 而且会给你的技术栈带来很多额外阻力
but that often overkill and adds a lot of friction into your tech stack.
所以系统的最后一部分就是评估器-优化器模式
So the last part of the system is the evaluator optimizer pattern,
这大概也是整个系统里最花哨的一块
which probably is the most fancy one from all of this.
基本上它包含了 12 次对语言模型的调用
And basically, it contains 12 LLM calls,
而且这一点非常重要
and this is really important.
它包含两个不同的上下文窗口，对吧
It contains two different context windows, right?
我们有写作者和审稿者
We have the writer and the reviewer,
基本流程是写作者先写出初稿，然后审稿者
where basically the writer first writes the draft and the reviewer,
在一个完全不同的上下文窗口中
with a completely different context window,
接收这份初稿并对其进行审阅
takes the draft and reviews it.
这对避免偏见非常关键，因为语言模型通常会对自己
And this is super important to avoid bias because LLMs usually tend to be biased in liking
已经写过的内容产生偏好
what they've already written.
所以只要把内容放进一个全新的上下文窗口
So by just putting that into a completely new context window,
就可以消除这种偏见
they can remove that bias.
那么基本上它是怎么运作的呢
So basically, how does this work?
审稿者会检查草稿是否遵循了写作指南
The reviewer checks adherence of the draft against the guideline,
也就是用户输入的要求，以及是否符合研究内容
which is the user input, against the research,
这主要是为了消除幻觉
basically to remove hallucinations,
还会对照各类配置档案
and against the profiles,
比如结构、术语和人物设定这些配置档案
those structure terminology and character profiles,
以确保草稿真正遵守这些要求
so we ensure that it adheres to it.
接着是编辑环节，而编辑通常就是写作者本人
And then the editor, which is often the writer itself,
他会根据审稿意见进行修改，然后在我们的示例中会把这个循环跑三
applies the reviews, and then we run this loop in our examples three,
四次，来完成整篇内容的写作
four times to basically write the post,
审阅它、编辑它、优化它，等等等等
review it, edit it, optimize it, and so on and so forth,
有点类似一个微调优化循环
similar to like a fine-tuning optimization loop.
还有一些我们在实践中总结的小技巧，比如只要在工作
And a few tricks here that we absorb over time is that just by keeping in our working
目录里保留所有这些版本
directory all those versions,
这就很有帮助，因为写作是主观的
it helps because writing is subjective,
而且如果你把审稿者的意见用得太激进
and often if you apply this reviewer too aggressively,
结果可能会变成一种你根本不喜欢的风格，你懂的
it might make it... you might just not like it, you know?
所以你会想在这些版本之间对比，挑出自己最喜欢的那一个
So you want to look around the less versions and pick the one that you like the most.
同样地，因为写作是主观的
And again, because writing is subjective,
评估器-优化器模式通常会配合一个评分来工作
usually the evaluator-optimizer pattern works with a score.
基本做法是审稿者会给当前输入打一个分
So basically, the reviewer gives a score to the input,
然后你不断循环，直到分数达到某个特定阈值
and you loop until you reach upon a specific threshold.
但由于创作类工作本身很主观
But because creative work is subjective,
这个阈值其实很难量化，对吧
that threshold is very hard to quantify, right?
于是这个循环就会变得噪声很大、不太可靠
And this loop becomes very noisy and not reliable,
所以我们发现，直接设定一个固定的迭代次数会更简单，然后让
and we realize that it's just easier to just put a fixed number of iterations and let the
用户如果愿意，可以再手动多跑几轮
user run these iterations again manually if it just wants to.
接下来我们稍微深入一点，看一下审稿者是如何工作的
And now, let's dig a bit deeper into how the reviewer works.
基本上，它的输入包括
So basically, as input,
当前这篇内容的状态
it has the current state of the post.
然后作为上下文，它会拿到写作指南
Next, as context, it gets the guideline,
研究内容以及各类配置档案
the research, and the profiles,
这些基本上就是写作者需要参考的所有信息
which basically, it's what the writer needs to look around,
也就是写作者必须遵守的规则
and they are basically the rules the writer needs to follow.
而它的输出实际上是一组 Pydantic 对象，对吧
And the output is actually a set of Pydantic objects, right?
我认为这是这里最有意思的部分
And I think this is the most interesting part here,
也就是你会强制语言模型输出一个结构化对象列表
is that you actually constrain the LLM to output a list of structured objects,
这非常强大，因为如果你把一个 Pydantic 对象提供给语言模型
and this is powerful because if you give a Pydantic object to an LLM,
Pydantic 对象有个特性，你可以在每个属性下面加一个字段
Pydantic objects have this property where you can put a field under each attribute and
来明确说明这个字段的含义
actually explain what that field means.
所以这本质上是一种提示词工程技巧，可以更好地引导语言模型
So basically, this is a prompt engineering technique which guides the LLM a lot better
真正理解返回对象中每个属性应该包含什么内容
into actually understanding what each attribute of the return object actually needs to contain.
比如我们的审稿模型里有 profile、location 和 comment 这些属性
So for example, our review model has this profile location and comment attributes,
一个示例输出可能是
and an example output is,
比如“在第二段我们违反了术语配置档案，因为语言模型使用了 leverage band 这个词”
for example, we violated the terminology profile on paragraph two where the LLM used the leverage band term.
这样一来，编辑
And like this, the editor,
在拿到这些审稿意见时
when it gets these reviews,
就能非常清楚地知道到底违反了什么
will understand exactly what it violated.
而且从我们的测试来看，使用这种结构化的方式要容易得多，实际上
And from our test, we realized that it's a lot easier to use this structured... actually,
这种结构化输出的性能也远好于单纯让语言模型
it's a lot more performant to use this structured output than just letting the LLM,
随便吐出一大段自由格式的内容
I don't know, spit out whatever it wants.
同样，你可以在这个 Python 文件里查看对应的代码
Again, you can check this code within this Python file.
代码本身其实很简单
The code itself is pretty simple,
所以我就不在这里花时间深入讲解了
so unfortunately, I won't have time to dig too deep into it.
接着说编辑这一侧
And now on the editor part,
它会拿到这份 Pydantic 对象列表以及当前内容的状态
basically, it gets this list of Pydantic objects and the current state of the post,
同时它也会拿到写作者一开始拥有的全部上下文，因为编辑
and also it gets all the context that the writer initially has because the editor is
实际上就是写作者本人，对吧
actually the writer itself, right?
这很像一个写作团队里作者和编辑协作的方式
This is similar to how a team of writers and editors would work.
我写好一稿，交给编辑团队
I write something, I give it to a team of editors,
然后拿到审稿意见，再据此修改
I get the reviews, and I apply them.
还有一点很重要：审稿意见并不是一视同仁的，对吧
And another important thing is that reviews are not created equals, right?
尤其是人们总喜欢对所有东西都提意见
Especially people like to give reviews on everything,
语言模型在这点上也一样
usually, and this also is true for the LLMs.
而且因为我们会循环好几轮
And because we loop for a couple of times,
我们发现给这些审稿意见设定优先级非常关键
we realize that it's super important to put the priority on them.
一般来说，我们总是先优先考虑写作指南
So usually, we always want to prioritize the guideline first,
也就是用户输入的要求
which is the user input,
然后是研究内容，最后才是配置档案
then the research, and then the profile.
当不同审稿意见在同一段落或同一句话上发生冲突时
And this is super powerful when those reviews clash on the same paragraphs or on the same
这种优先级策略就非常有用
sentences and things like this.
这样我们就知道该采纳哪条意见、舍弃哪条
Then we know what to pick up and what to apply.
好的，同样你可以在这个 Python 文件里查看整个系统
Okay, again, you can check the system,
包括提示词，在代码仓库中的这个 Python 文件里
the prompt within this Python file, within the repo.
这里有一个具体示例，我们可以看到 v0 版本的帖子
And here is a concrete example where we can see the post v0,
也就是在进入评估器-优化器循环之前，语言模型最初吐出的内容
which is basically what the LLM spits out before the evaluator optimizer loop,
而这是经过四轮审阅迭代之后的样子
and this is how it looks like after four reviewing iterations.
可以看到文本已经被很好地排版成适合领英的格式
So we can see that the text is nicely formatted for LinkedIn.
此外，第一句
Also, the first sentence,
也就是最重要的那一句
which is the most important,
变得更有冲击力之类的
is punchier and things like this.
这一点对帖子的前半部分和后半部分同样成立
This is valid also for the first part of the post and also for the second part of the post.
同样，它会调整结构
Again, it modified the structure,
用词等等所有内容，使其整体更像
the wording, everything to look more
一篇你在领英上会看到的帖子
about something that you would expect on LinkedIn.
同样，你可以在 examples 目录中查看整篇帖子以及从 0 到 4 的所有版本
And again, you can check the whole post and all the versions from zero to four within the examples directory.
最后让我实际给你展示一下这个目录长什么样
And ultimately, let me actually show you how this directory looks like.
为了测试这段代码
So to test this code,
你实际上有三个层级
you actually have three levels.
所以我写了一个简单的 make 命令来检查一切是否正常运行
So I created a simple make command just to check that everything works.
所以没什么花里胡哨的东西
So no, nothing crazy here.
如果这一整套能端到端跑通
If this works end to end,
就说明你的代码在本地是能跑的
it means your code works locally.
你可以把这个交给 Claude Code 来让你的代码跑起来
You can pass that to Claude Code to make your code work.
我们的服务方式和研究智能体的工作方式类似
So we serve similar to how the research agent works,
把所有东西都交给一个 MCP 服务器的提示词
everything to an MCP server prompt.
然后我们把这个 MCP 和一个写帖子技能连在一起
And then we connected this MCP with a write post skill.
但问题是这个要花大概三
And the thing is that this takes like three,
四分钟才能跑完
four minutes to run.
所以我已经提前跑过了，免得浪费你的时间
So I already ran it to avoid wasting your time.
不过这里是你该怎么运行它
But here is how you can run it.
基本上你先拿到这个写帖子技能
So basically, you take this write post skill.
然后就像我们对 LLM 那样，我们拿
And just as the LLM, we take,
比如说之前用过的那个同样的示例
for example, the same example that we took.
我们复制它的相对路径
We copy the relative path.
然后让它使用那里面的这份指南
And we ask it to use the guideline from this there.
接着它就会知道要把这份指南和与之相关的研究一起拿过来
And then basically, it will know to pick up the guideline and the research associated with
然后据此写一篇帖子
it and write a post.
输出结果就在这里
And the output is here.
你可以看到我们有四个版本的帖子
As you can see, we have the four versions of the post,
实际上是五个版本的帖子
actually five versions of the post,
还有那份指南
and also the guideline,
我觉得这部分是最有意思的
which I think is the most interesting one.
所以基本上你可以看到
So basically, as you can see,
与其只是礼貌地让 LLM 随便写点什么
instead of just like kindly asking LLM to write about something,
你得非常明确地告诉它你到底要什么
you need to be very explicit about what you want from it.
所以你要给出一个切入角度
So you need to put an angle,
你想要的目标受众
the target audience that you want,
你真正想要覆盖的关键点
key points that you actually want to cover,
语气风格之类的东西
the tone, and things like this.
还有一个字数限制，它会覆盖掉那些静态配置的其他写作画像
And actually, a constraint of characters that overrides the other profiles that are static.
也就是说在系统提示词里写明，在这份指南里
So encoding in the system prompt that within this guideline,
你确实可以在想要不同效果时覆盖默认画像
you actually can override the default profiles if you want something different.
基本上在这里你可以放飞自我，输入任何你想要的东西
And basically, here, you can go wild and input anything you want,
但我只是想强调一点
but I just wanted to highlight,
你确实得花点心思把这些想清楚
like, you actually need to put in some effort to think it through, you know?
如果你不想听起来像真正的 AI 烂文，你就不能把一切完全丢给自动化
You cannot just fully automate everything if you don't want to sound like a true AI slob.
好
Okay.
在此之上我们还做了一个小小的图片生成器
And on top of this, we actually have like a small image generator.
我们在这上面没花太多功夫
We haven't put a lot of effort into this,
但这个提示词会先用这个写作工作流生成帖子，然后再让
but this prompt actually generates the post using this writing workflow and then asks
另一个工具自动为这篇帖子生成一张图片
another tool to automatically generate an image for that post.
好，那我们继续往下
Okay. So now to move on.
总结一下我们在写作工作流上做了什么
So just to wrap up on what we build on the writing workflow,
我们搭建了这个写作工作流流水线，它会生成
we build this writing workflow of pipeline that generates,
审阅并编辑帖子
reviews, and edits the post,
这些同样可以应用到任何类型的内容上
which again, you can apply to any type of content.
我们几乎在各种内容类型上都测试过，效果都很好
We tested it with almost every type of content and it works really well.
你只需要调整一下画像配置
You just need to adapt basically the profiles,
示例之类的东西
the examples, and things like this.
然后我们也学到了
And then we learn, like,
如何控制生成过程
how to control the generation,
指南、画像配置
the guideline, the profiles,
以及少样本示例
and the few-shot examples.
同样地，对于不同的内容类型
Again, for different content types,
你需要对这些做相应调整
you will need to adapt this.
以及如何把这一切作为 MCP 服务器和技能来对外提供
And then how to serve everything as an MCP server and skills.
没错，对于这个本地示例来说
And yes, for this local example,
你完全可以只用技能来完成所有事情
you could do everything through skills.
你并不真的需要 MCP 服务器才能让它跑起来
You don't really need MCP servers to make it work,
但根据我的经验
but from my experience,
MCP 服务器能让你更轻松地分发逻辑，因为技能更像是你的本地
MCP servers help you distribute logic a lot easier because skills are like your local
配置、本地小黑科技，对你自己来说很好用
setup, your local hack setup that works great for you.
但如果你想分发业务逻辑
But if you want to distribute business logic,
你肯定不想跟别人说
you don't really want to ask someone,
嘿，先把这些技能下下来
hey, download those skills,
再在那边装这些 UV 依赖
install these UV dependencies over there,
然后把那些 CLI 工具也接上
plug in those CLI tools.
哦对了，你还得要这些凭证
Oh no, you also need those credentials.
这样一来要大规模分发就会很快变成一团乱麻
And it quickly becomes a mess to distribute this at scale.
而 MCP 服务器解决的就是这个问题
And MCP servers solve that problem.
而技能可以帮你个性化地使用这些能力
And skills can help you personalize how you use that.
基本上如果你希望技能不只是一个提示词，而是真正去跑那段代码
Basically, if you want the skill to be more than a prompt and actually run that code,
这是可行的，但如果太复杂，配置起来也会很快变成一团糟
it works, but it can become a quick mess to set it up if it's too complicated.
所以现在我们进入系统的第四部分，也就是可观测性
So now let's move on to part four of the system, which is observability,
更具体地说是监控和评估
more exactly monitoring and evals.
我们会用写作工作流作为评估的示例
So we will use the writing workflow as an example for evals,
而监控这块我们对两边都做了
and we did monitoring for both.
关于监控我们会讲得很快，因为在理论层面没太多可说的
So for monitoring, we will go really quick over this because theory-wise there's not much to say.
核心思路是，监控背后的核心问题在于
So the idea is that the core problem behind monitoring,
在我看来，当我们开始使用智能体和工作流时，这个问题被彻底放大了
which in my opinion exploded when we started to use agents and workflow,
那就是仅靠日志来调试工作流和智能体非常困难
is that debugging workflows and agents purely through the logs is hard.
就我个人来说，我很难只靠终端里那些东西看明白发生了什么
I personally can't really understand what's going on inside the terminal,
尤其是当你看到智能体的那些“正在思考”时
especially when you see those thinking of the agent,
它把大量细节都藏起来了
which hides a lot of stuff.
所以只靠日志来调试到底发生了什么会变得非常痛苦
So it quickly becomes painful to debug what's going on just using the logs.
所以你基本上需要一个工具来好好监控这些东西，把所有的 trace 都记录下来
So basically, you need some tool to monitor this nicely that captures all your traces,
比如所有的 LLM 调用和工具调用
such as all the LLM and tool calls,
你的输入、输出以及各种元数据
your input, output, your metadata.
它会捕获这次运行的所有信息
It captures everything about your run,
还包括延迟和成本跟踪
and also latency and cost tracking.
另外一个额外好处是，它还会存储你的 trace，以便在此基础上构建一个 AI 评估层
And as a bonus, it also stores your traces to build an AI eval layer on top of everything,
这个我待会儿会再详细展开一点
which I will dig more into it a bit later.
那现在我们来实际看一下我们的监控日志
So now let's actually look into our monitoring logs.
我们用 Opik 来监控我们的两个智能体
So we used Opik to monitor both our agents,
也就是研究智能体和写作工作流
the research, and the writing workflow.
我们来仔细看一下
And let's look into it,
因为这样会更容易理解
because it's a lot easier to understand like this.
在监控方面通常会有三个大的概念
So for monitoring, usually you have like three big concepts.
你会有这些线程
You have those threads,
在我们的用例里它基本上就是
which is basically, in our use case,
写一篇端到端帖子整个工作流的抽象
is like the whole workflow of writing an end-to-end post,
比如从帖子本身加上配图开始
like starting with the post itself plus the image.
比如你可以看到
For example, as you can see,
这个工作流里有 44 条消息
this workflow has 44 messages,
基本上捕捉了用户和语言模型之间所有来回交互
which basically captures all the bouncing around between the user and the LLM.
你可以更直观地把它看成一个对话线程
You can more intuitively see it as a conversation thread,
这就是为什么它被叫作线程
which that's why it's called a thread, you know.
然后你还有 trace
And then you have the traces,
在这里你就可以真正深入挖掘到底发生了什么
and here you can actually dig deeper into what's going on.
所以一个线程里包含多个 trace 对吧
So a thread contains multiple traces, right?
而在一个 trace 里面你可以进一步挖掘里面发生的事情
And within a trace, you can actually dig into what's going on.
比如说对于一个 generatePost 这个 trace
So for example, for a generatePost trace,
这里我们有 generatePost 调用的高层概览
here we have the high level overview generatePost call,
在这里我们能看到它运行花了多长时间
where we can see how long it took to run,
消耗了多少 token
how many tokens it consumed,
运行成本是多少
how much it cost to run.
在这里我们还能看到底层发生的所有工具调用和 LLM 调用
And here we can see all the tool calls and LLM calls that happened under the hood, right?
所以我们可以看到用了哪些模型
So we can see the models used,
每个模型的成本和延迟
the cost per model, the latency per model,
以及所有这些信息
and all of that.
在右侧我们还能看到系统的高层输入和输出
And on the right, we can also see the high level input and output of the system,
一些元数据和 token 使用情况
some metadata, the token usage,
基本上就是那次运行中发生的所有事情
and basically everything that happened within that run,
这会非常有助于你快速理解到底发生了什么
which helps you a lot to quickly understand what's happening, right?
对于研究智能体我们也有类似的东西
And we have something similar for the research agent as well.
在这里线程要容易理解得多 因为
Here, the thread is a lot easier to understand because,
比如我们有这个最新的线程 它捕捉了所有这些工具调用
for example, we have this latest thread which captures all those tool calls,
基本上就是所有深度研究工具的调用
basically all the deep research tool calls,
包括生成最终报告的工具调用以及所有来回交互
the tool call that creates the final report and all the bouncing around,
然后是这些线程
and then the threads,
还有这些 trace 它们只包含单个工具调用
the traces, which have just single tool calls,
它们只捕捉一次工具调用
that they capture just a single tool call,
你可以看到每次深度研究工具调用只对应一次 LLM 调用
whereas you can see we have just one LLM call per deep research tool call.
好 现在我们来讲 AI 评测
Okay, so now let's move on to AI evals.
我想先从为什么评测很重要讲起
So I want to start with why evals matter,
因为这不一定是个很酷的话题
because it's not necessarily a cool topic,
但它能给你的系统带来非常大的帮助
but it can do a lot on your system.
我们还是用写作工作流这个例子
So basically, let's take our writing workflow example.
假设我们想检查它到底效果如何
Let's say that we want to check how well it works, right?
我们一开始总是凭感觉做个 vibe checking
We always start with vibes, with vibe checking.
当我们这么做 只生成一篇帖子时
When we do, and when we generate just one post,
我们读一读 然后说
we read it, we say that,
嗯 挺好 很棒 能用
hey, it's cool, awesome, it works.
然后当我们有 10 篇帖子时
Well, then we have 10 posts,
我们可能会读 也可能不会
we read them, maybe, maybe not,
可能读两篇 可能读三篇 然后就算完事 并且认为其他的也都没问题
maybe we read two, maybe we read three and call it a day and say it works for the others as well.
但当我们想在 100 篇帖子上检查效果时
And then when we want to check how well it works in 100 posts,
很快就会发现根本做不到
it quickly becomes impossible.
而且想象一下 你一开始是这么做的
And just imagine that you do this at the beginning,
但随着系统不断演进
but as you evolve your system,
你开始接入更多功能
you start to plug in more features,
对吧 而每个新功能都有可能把一切都搞崩
right, and every feature can just break everything.
这在软件工程里是标准做法
And yeah, this is standard practice in software engineering,
但在这里你是和提示词打交道 随便某个地方多了一个词就可能把
but here you work with prompts and just one word somewhere randomly can just break all
你的所有功能都搞坏 如果你不小心的话
your features if you're not careful,
所以你需要在上面再加一层保护
you know, and you need this layer on top of it.
基本上 评测可以分成三个大的层次
So basically evals fit in three big, big layers.
第一层是优化
So we have optimization,
它和训练一个模型非常类似
which is very similar like to training a model.
所以我们有这一层 AI 评测 让我们可以量化
So basically we have this AI evals layer which lets us quantify how well our writing
写作工作流写领英帖子的效果
workflow writes LinkedIn posts, right?
然后当我们想改进它时
Then when we want to improve it,
我们会有一个分数告诉我们
we have a score which tells us that,
我们是不是在朝正确方向前进 还是根本没进步
hey, do we move in the right directions or we don't move?
所以每次改动我们都会跑这一层 AI 评测 来判断是变好了还是变差了
So on every change, we run this AI evals layer and we know if we did better or worse.
下一层是回归测试
The next layer is regression testing,
它基本上类似传统软件工程里的测试 当我们开始
which is basically similar to testing classic software engineering where whenever we start
开发一个新功能时
working on a new feature,
要确保不会破坏现有功能
we just ensure that we don't break current functionality.
第三层就是在生产环境里对实时 trace 运行这些评测
And the layer tree will be to actually run this in production on live traces to actually
当用户真正使用你的系统时 能实时拿到告警 错误和各种报警信息
get warnings and errors and alarms and all of that when users actually use your system.
而在实际中 这和普通的单元测试 集成测试 回归测试不同的地方在于
And in reality, how this is different from like normal unit integration and regression
一切都是从评测数据集开始的
test is that everything starts from the eval data set, right?
所以这是一个数据问题
So this is a data problem.
我们实际上是在这里构建一个模型
We actually build a model here.
下面是我们为领英帖子构建它的方式 我们很幸运已经
So here is how we build it for our LinkedIn posts where we were lucky enough to actually
拥有了这些数据
already have the data.
所以我从自己的领英里抽取了 20 篇真实帖子
So I extracted 20 real posts from my LinkedIn.
为什么是 20 篇 我觉得对一个 workshop 来说这个数量已经够大了
Why 20? I said that is a big enough number for a workshop,
但在真实场景里我们可能至少需要 100 篇
but in reality, we'll probably need to go at least 100.
然后我对其中的写作指南和研究过程做了逆向工程
Then I reversed engineered the guideline and the research.
基本上就是先从帖子里抽取出写作指南 然后在这个指南上运行深度研究智能体
Basically, I took the guideline from the post and then I ran the deep research agent on
去找到支撑那篇帖子的所有必要信息
top of the guideline to find whatever I need to support that post.
然后我再生成输出
And then I generated the output.
也就是说 我把写作指南和研究结果作为输入来生成新的帖子
So basically, I put the guideline and the research as inputs and generated new posts.
这点非常重要 因为我们真正想看到的是你真实系统的产出结果
And this is super important because we actually want to see results from your real system.
当你想生成某种合成数据时
And when you want to generate synthetic data of some sort,
千万不要让 LLM 直接生成输出
never ask the LLM to directly generate the output.
要让它帮你生成输入
Always ask it to help you generate the input,
而不是输出
but never the output.
你要的是来自真实系统的输出 因为最终你测试的就是它
You want the output from your real system because that's what you're testing ultimately.
然后我逐个查看这些输出 给每条打上通过或失败的二元标签 并写上两三句评语
And then I looked around and labeled each output with binary pass and fail labels and two,
说明我为什么给它通过或失败的标签
three sentences critique on why exactly I gave it a pass or fail label to it.
通常我在发现第一个错误时就会停下来
And usually, I stop when I find the first error.
这样对我打标签更轻松 也更方便 LLM 理解我一旦发现问题就会停下
It's just easier for me while labeling and also for the LLM to understand that whenever I
看到第一个失败样本时我就停下来
see the first fail, I stop at it.
我把为什么失败写成三句话然后继续往下做
I write white failed into three sentences and move on.
最终我把所有这些数据划分成训练集和深度测试集
And ultimately, I split all of this into a train depth test split because ultimately,
要记住这里我们是在构建一个机器学习AI模型
remember that here we're building a machine learning AI model.
所以我们需要按这种方式来对待它
So we needed to treat it as such.
因此我们需要一个经典的数据集划分
So we need a classic split.
只有当我们有了这个数据集以及这些划分之后
And only when we have this data set and these splits,
我们才能真正构建评估器并评估这个评估器本身
we can actually build the evaluator and evaluate the evaluator,
但在大多数情况下不知为何
which most often, for some reason,
当人们在构建LLM评判器时
when they build LLM judges,
他们觉得可以直接跳过这最后一步
they think they can just skip this last step,
而这一步可能是最重要的一步
which is probably the most important one.
再强调一次这里最重要也最有意思的是我们创建的数据集
And again, what's the most important and interesting here is the data set that we created
因为在此基础上真正创建一个LLM评判器
because actually creating an LLM judge out of this,
如果你已经有了数据集
if you have the data set,
就会变得非常容易
is just very easy.
好现在我们来看一下这个LLM评判器在当前场景下是如何工作的
Okay, so now let's see how this LLM judge would work for our current scenario.
作为输入它会接收需要打标签的生成帖子
So as input, it will take the generated post that it needs to label,
还会接收人物画像研究材料和写作指南
but also the profiles, research, and guidelines.
这点非常重要因为LLM评判器实际上需要理解生成这篇帖子的上下文
And this is super important because the LLM judge actually needs to understand the context
也就是用来生成这篇帖子的那些信息
used to generate this post.
最终它会输出通过
And ultimately, it outputs the pass,
或未通过的标签以及评语
fail label plus the critique.
基本上和我们数据集里的标签完全一致
Basically, exactly the same labels as our data set.
然后我们会把数据集中的一部分作为少样本示例传给它
And then we pass, as few-shot examples,
也就是训练集的那一部分
our train split from the data set.
这一步是最关键的因为LLM评判器的系统提示词可以非常简单
And this is the most important one because the system prompt of the LLM judge can be
只要有合适的少样本示例来告诉LLM评判器
extremely simple if it has the right few-shot examples in place that tells the LLM judge
它应该做出什么样的判断
what decisions to take.
少样本示例大致长这样
So the few-shot examples look like this.
它们包含写作者的输入
They have the writer input,
也就是写作指南和研究材料
which is the guideline and research,
也就是我们写作工作流系统的输入
so the input to our writing workflow system,
然后是写作者的输出
then the writer output,
也就是工作流生成的帖子以及对应的标签
which is basically the generated post of the workflow, and the labels.
所以在少样本示例中
So in the few-shot examples,
我们同样包含这些标签
we also have the labels,
包括通过和未通过的标签
the pass and fail label,
以及两三句关于该标签的评语
and the two, three sentences critique about the label.
就是这样
And this is it.
你可以在这个文件里查看我们的系统提示词
You can check out our system prompt within this file,
但里面没有什么花哨的东西
but there's nothing fancy.
这里最重要的部分还是构建数据集
The most important part from this is building the data set.
我们最后一步是实际衡量评判器的可靠性因为归根结底
And our last step is to actually measure the judge reliability because ultimately what we
我们在这里做的事情就是把LLM评判器当作一个二分类器对吧
did here, the LLM judge is just a binary classifier, right?
我们输出通过和未通过这两种标签
We output pass and fail labels.
所以是的我们用了LLM评判器因为说实话这样做很容易
So yeah, we used an LLM judge because the reality is that it's easy,
但我们也完全可以用任何其他能完成任务并输出这些
but we could have just used any other model that gets the job done and can output these
通过和未通过标签的模型
pass and fail labels.
最终当我们在衡量评判器的可靠性时
And ultimately, when we measure judge reliability,
我们的最终目标是让LLM评判器和领域专家保持一致
our final goal is to align the LLM judge with the domain expert.
那我们要如何做到这一点呢
And how we will do that,
我们会通过用深度测试集的划分来测试它
we will do that by testing it against the depth test data set splits.
这个过程和训练其他任何二分类器都非常相似
So this is a process very similar to training any other binary classifier.
这里没有什么新东西
There's nothing new here,
只是LLM评判器这个说法听起来更花哨一点
just the word LLM judge is fancier.
所以我们基本上就是用深度测试集的各个划分来测试LLM评判器
So what we do basically is test the LLM judge against the depth test data set splits and
然后使用F1分数也就是精确率和召回率的组合来衡量
then use F1 score, which is a combination of precision and recall to actually measure how
LLM评判器在这些划分上的表现有多好
well the LLM judge performs against these splits.
整个流程大致如下
And the process looks like this.
首先我们在深度测试集划分上运行LLM评判器
So we first run the LLM judge on the depth split,
计算F1分数
compute the F1 score,
然后调整LLM评判器以及提示示例以最大化这个F1分数
and adjust the LLM judge and prompt examples to maximize this F1 score.
因为很可能在我们刚开始这个流程时
Because most probably, when we first start this process,
F1分数会比较低
the F1 score will be low,
而我们的目标基本上就是把这个分数尽量提高
and we basically want to get a score as high as possible.
我们会不断重复直到结果收敛
And we repeat until we converge.
通常你需要这样做好几轮
Usually you need to do this a couple of times.
当你觉得已经调好了LLM评判器可以上线时
And when you think you're done and the LLM judge is ready to go,
你就把它跑在测试集划分上作为最后的验证步骤对吧
you run it on the test split as the final validation step, right?
这基本上就是在训练一个机器学习模型
Basically training a machine learning model.
这样它就可以在新数据上运行了
And now it's ready to run on new data.
所以在完成这些步骤之后
So after we go through these steps,
我们就得到了这个LLM评判器
we have the LLM judge,
它已经可以在新的数据样本上运行
which is ready to run on new samples of data,
它会输出二元的通过或未通过以及对应的评语
which will just output the binary pass or fail, and the critique.
现在把这一节的所有内容串起来就是我们先构建数据集
Now, like, to wire everything together that we had in this section is that we first build
然后基于数据集构建LLM评判器
the dataset, then based on that we build the LLM judge,
接着对评判器进行校准
then we calibrate the judge,
只有在那之后我们才能把它跑在真实数据上
and only after that we can run it on real data.
通常所有这些步骤都会由某个可观测性平台来管理
And usually all the steps are managed by some observability platform.
我们这里用的是Opik但你也可以用任何其他平台或者自建一套系统
We used here Opik, but you can use any other platform or just build something in-house.
这个具体选择并不重要
It doesn't really matter,
关键在于所有东西应该由一个统一的平台来管理
but the idea is everything should be managed by a cohesive platform.
好那现在作为一个快速演示
Okay, so now as a quick demo,
我们尽可能去模拟这个校准步骤
let's emulate as much as possible this calibration step,
因为LLM评判器其实已经校准好了
because the LLM judge is already calibrated,
所以我只会给你展示它在评估集划分上的表现
so I will just show you how the LLM judge performs on the eval split.
在底层我们通过Opik
So under the hood with Opik,
构建了一个非常简单的评估框架
we built a very simple evaluation harness,
它允许我们执行这些校准步骤然后再把它跑在生产环境的调用轨迹上
where it allows us to run these calibration steps and then run it on production traces.
所以在实际情况中这段代码
So in reality, the code is,
对于我们的用例来说相当直接明了
for our use case, is pretty straightforward.
在它运行的同时我先简单带你看一下
So just to show you around a bit until it runs.
好现在它实际在做的事情是
Okay, so actually what it does now,
它会拿到所有生成出来的帖子对吧
it takes all the generated posts, right?
然后把LLM评判器应用到所有这些生成帖子上
It passes the LLM judge on top of all those generated posts,
接着我想给你展示的是这个F1分数
and then what I wanted to show you is this F1 score.
在这里我们根据LLM评判器的输出与我们
Where basically we compute an F1 score based on the outputs from the LLM judge against our
数据集中的标签进行对比来计算F1分数
labels from the dataset,
我觉得更有意思的是能很快看到我们的数据集长什么样子以便获得
which I think is more interesting to see how our dataset looks like really quickly to get
一个直观感受
a sense of it.
所以基本上这里我们展示的是数据集中的一个样本
So basically here we have like a single sample within our dataset,
更有意思的是我们有帖子媒体内容的链接
where what's more interesting is like we have a link to the media of the post,
还有指南的链接以及生成帖子本身的链接
to the guideline, to the generated post,
基本上把我们作为输入和输出所需要的一切都用链接串起来了
basically links to everything that we need as input and output,
既服务于深度研究智能体也服务于写作工作流
both for the deep research agent and the writing workflow.
然后在这个范围内
And then just putting this scope,
我们把它们作为少样本示例接入进去
we plug them in as a few-shot examples,
无论是给帖子生成器用还是给评估器用
either for the post generator or for the evaluator,
或者比如用于开发集划分之类的用途
or for example for the dev split and things like this.
这就是我们如何谨慎地在LLM评判器
So this is how we are careful that we do the splits the right way between the LLM judge
和生成器之间做好数据划分的方式
and also the generator.
为了简单起见我们把所有这些文件都在本地的这个YAML文件里关联起来
And for simplicity, we have all those files linked together in this YAML file here locally
放在GitHub里这样你可以查看所有内容并进行试验
within GitHub, so you can check everything and play it,
试验并以最小配置非常轻松地跑起整个流程
play it, and run everything very easily with minimal configuration.
好的那么如果我们回到终端里
Okay, so if we go back into the terminal,
我们看到它得到了一个近乎完美的分数
we saw that it had like a perfect score.
所以现在我们真正把它跑在测试集上目标是确认我们的LLM
So now let's actually run this on the test split and the goal here is to see that our LLM
评判器没有对其过拟合
judge did not overfit it.
我们已经在开发集上跑过了
So we ran it on the dev split,
得到了完美分数
we get the perfect score.
通常这是一个强烈信号表明它过拟合了
Usually this is a high signal that it overfitted,
所以除非测试集上的F1分数不是1或者接近1
so unless the F1 score on the test split is not one or around one,
否则就意味着我们的LLM评判器过拟合了
it means that our LLM judge is overfitted.
所以再一次和之前的流程类似
So again, similar to the process before,
基本上是完全相同的步骤只是这次跑在测试集上
it's basically the exact same steps but now ran on the test split.
那我们来看一下最终的F1分数
So let's see the final F1 score,
又是1这很好
which is again one, which is good.
分数之所以这么高是因为我们每个划分只用了五个样本
And the scores are so good because we do this just on five samples per split,
但如果你扩展你的数据划分
but if you expand your split,
至少应该有二三十个样本
which you should have at least like 20-30 samples,
那分数很可能就不会这么完美了
the score probably would not be perfect.
好接下来我来展示一下这些实验在Opik里的样子
Okay, and let me actually show how these experiments look inside Opik.
好的当然那么在决定是否采用这个评判器时
Yeah, sure. Does the decision of employing the judge,
你用的随机F1分数阈值是多少才会说它是完美的
what was the random F1 score you used to say it was perfect,
如果它们在现实中总是完美的话
if they were in reality always perfect?
嗯我觉得最重要的是你在开发集上的F1分数和
Yeah, I think that the most important is like the dynamics between the F1 score on your
测试集上的F1分数之间的变化关系
dev split and the dynamics on your test split,
因为过拟合当模型过拟合时
because the overfit, when the model is overfitted,
实际上就是看这两者之间是如何对比的
is actually like how is compared between the two.
比如说如果正如我刚才讲的那样
For example, if it, as I said,
如果它在开发集上分数很高而在测试集上分数很低
if it has like a very big score on the dev split and a low score on the test split,
那就说明它过拟合了
it means it overfitted,
但分数本身通常和你自己的数据高度相关
but the score itself usually is very correlated with your own data.
所以比如说你对某个分数感到满意
So for example, you're pleased with...
你是说你更看重的是模型整体的相对表现
You say what you're looking for is more like the relativity of the model at all,
比如它们是不是大致在同一个水平区间
like if they are more than the same brand.
对对对，没错。所以这跟绝对值本身关系不大，对，没错
Yeah, yeah, exactly. So it's less to do with the absolute value. Yeah, exactly.
绝对值通常和你的数据高度相关
The absolute value usually is very correlated with your data.
一般来说在测试集上你会说
Usually on the test split you say,
好这个F1分数对我来说已经足够好了
okay, this F1 score is good enough for me.
然后你再在测试集上运行看看测试集上是不是也能得到同样的F1分数
And then you run on the test split to see that you have the same F1 score on the test split as well.
好那么通常在这类可观测性平台里
Okay, so again, usually with these observability platforms,
你会有一个实验标签页可以在里面运行类似微调
you have these experiments tab where you can actually run like experiments similar to fine
那种老派实验追踪器的实验
tuning experiment trackers from the old school.
比如这里我们就有开发集和测试集的实验
And for example, here we have the dev and test experiments.
那我们打开刚刚跑过的测试实验
So let's open the test experiment that we just ran.
在这里我们可以看到二元LLM评判器的输出以及我们的标签
And here we can actually see the output from the binary LLM judge and our label.
我们可以看到两者之间完全一致
And we can see that there's a perfect match between the two.
如果我们把鼠标悬停在这里
And if we hover over this,
还能看到评判器给出的评语
we can also see like the critique of the judge.
但实际上在这里我们只是在标签之间计算分数
But in reality here, we compute the score only between the labels.
而这些评语对我们更有用因为最终我们的目标是让人类
And this critique is more useful for us because ultimately our goal is us as humans to
查看这些结果并理解哪里出了问题
look over these results and understand what's going wrong.
在这个系统里
With the system.
然后作为最后一步
And then as a final step,
我还准备了一个在线模拟在里面我模拟了一些在线轨迹
I also prepared like a online simulation where I simulated some online traces
让LLM评判器真正跑在这些轨迹上从而得到二元标签和评语
where the LLM judge actually runs on top of them and you get the binary labels and the critique.
但问题是这要跑大概五分钟甚至更久因为它确实需要
But the thing is that this takes like five minutes or even more to run because it actually
真实地生成
needs to generate, for real,
生成所有帖子并在其上运行一个LLM评判器
it needs to generate all the posts and run an LLM judge on top of it.
所以我只在这里给你看一下我们的结果
So I'll just show you our results over here,
我把这些结果打包成了一个实验
which I bundled together as an experiment.
也就是这个在线测试评估套件在这里
So it's this online test evaluation suite where,
再比如说我们可以进一步深入查看
again, for example, just let us dig into it further.
你可以看到比如说
You can see, for example,
右侧是生成的帖子以及来自二元评判器的结果
the generated post here on the right and then the results from the binary from the judge
在那里我们能看到分数以及具体的评语
where we will find the score and the critique itself.
当然这个系统还远不完美
And of course, this system is not yet perfect.
我可能还需要进一步打磨因为在这些实时轨迹上
I probably need to refine it more because here on live traces,
如你所见说实话它有点失败
as you can see, it kind of failed, to be honest.
它只是给出了一个通过的F1分数
It just passed an F1 score.
它对所有轨迹都判定为通过而实际上我对这些模拟场景是有标签的
It just gave us a pass on all the traces while in reality I also have the labels for these simulated scenarios.
我们可以看到它其实是失败的
We can see that it failed.
我可能需要回到开发集
Probably I need to go back to the dev split,
用新的样本扩充开发集
expand the dev split with new samples.
比如我可以直接把这些样本拿过来放进开发集然后开始
For example, I could just take these samples and put them in the dev split and start
一遍遍地微调直到它真正奏效
refining it again and again until it actually works.
而且我时间也快不够了
And I'm kind of running out of time,
但你也可以用这个技能真正跑一个端到端的研究加写作演示
but you also have this skill to actually run a demo end-to-end research and writing.
你可以比如说
You can, for example,
写一份你想发帖主题的指南并把它作为
write a guideline about something that you want to write a post about and give that as the
这个技能的输入它只是一个文件系统就会知道要读取它并完成
input to this skill, which is just a file and it will know to pick up and to do the
研究然后继续写帖子
research and then continue to writing the post.
你也可以在Opik里观察到整个过程包括所有线程
And you can also observe that in Opik with all the threads,
轨迹以及所有这些信息
traces, and all of that.
然后嗯我想最后一步
And yeah, I guess that the final step,
如果你还没有这么做的话
if you haven't done so yet,
就是亲自打开这个GitHub代码仓库，把所有内容自己跑一遍
is to actually open up the GitHub repository, run everything yourself,
并且把代码读一读
and read the code.
因为如果不读代码的话
Because without reading the code,
我们很可能就无法真正理解里面到底发生了什么
most probably we won't really understand what's going inside.
所以你可以通过访问这个链接或者扫描这个二维码来完成这些操作
So you can do that by accessing this link or scanning the QR code.
当你准备好了并且想要更深入地构建这种类型的多智能体
And whenever you're ready and you want to go deeper into building this type of multi-agent
系统时，我们有一门智能体工程课程
systems, we have this agentic engineering course,
这门课程基本上就是本次工作坊的灵感来源
which basically was the inspiration for this workshop.
但在课程中，我们的目标其实是设计和构建可直接用于生产环境的智能体，而不是
But instead, our goal was actually to design and build production-ready agents and not
只是做一些小型的本地系统
just some small local systems.
在这门课中有34节课程
And within 34 lessons,
三个端到端的作品集项目
three end-to-end portfolio projects,
一份结业证书，以及一个可以直接和我们交流的Discord社区
a certificate, and a Discord community with access to us.
到目前为止，它被300多名学员评为满分五分
And so far it's rated five by five by 300 plus students.
如果你对我们说的还有疑问
And if you don't believe us,
前六节课可以免费试学
the first six lessons are free to try out.
你可以通过这个链接或者扫描二维码来访问课程
And you can access it using this link or scanning the QR code.
好的 那今天的工作坊就到这里结束
Yeah. And that's it for the workshop today.